<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<species-list>
    <species>
        <latin>Abies cephalonica</latin>
        <common>Grecian Pine</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <tag>evergreen</tag>
        <tag>coniferous</tag>
        <family>Pinaceae</family>
        <abstract>Abies cephalonica or Greek fir is a fir native to the mountains of Greece,
            primarily in the Peloponnesos and the island of Kefallonia, intergrading with the
            closely related Bulgarian fir further north in the Pindus mountains of northern Greece.
            It is a medium-size evergreen coniferous tree growing to 25–35 metres (82–115 ft) –
            rarely 40 m (130 ft) – tall and with a trunk diameter of up to 1 m (3 ft 3 in). It
            occurs at altitudes of 900–1,700 m (3,000–5,600 ft), on mountains with a rainfall of
            over 1,000 millimetres (39 in). The leaves are needle-like, flattened, 1.5–3.0 cm
            (0.6–1.2 in) long and 2 mm (0.08 in) wide by 0.5 mm (0.02 in) thick, glossy dark green
            above, and with two blue-white bands of stomata below. The tip of the leaf is pointed,
            usually fairly sharply but sometimes with a blunt tip, particularly on slow-growing
            shoots on older trees. The cones are 10–20 cm (4–8 in) long and 4 cm (1.6 in) broad,
            with about 150–200 scales, each scale with an exserted bract and two winged seeds; they
            disintegrate when mature to release the seeds. It is also closely related to Nordmann
            fir to the east in northern Turkey.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Abies_cephalonica_001.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Abies pinsapo</latin>
        <common>Spanish Fir</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <tag>evergreen</tag>
        <tag>coniferous</tag>
        <family>Pinaceae</family>
        <abstract>Abies pinsapo (Spanish fir) is a species of fir native to southern Spain and
            northern Morocco. Related to other species of Mediterranean firs, it is considered the
            Andalusian National Tree, and is native to the Andalusian mountains. In Spain, it
            appears at altitudes of 900–1,800 metres (3,000–5,900 ft) in the Sierra de Grazalema in
            the province of Cádiz and the Sierra de las Nieves and Sierra Bermeja, both near Ronda
            in the province of Málaga. In Morocco, it is limited to the Rif Mountains at altitudes
            of 1,400–2,100 metres (4,600–6,900 ft) on Jebel Tissouka and Jebel Tazaot.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Abies_pinsapo_var._tazaotana,_Wakehurst_Place,_UK_-_Diliff.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Acacia saligna</latin>
        <latin>Acacia cyanophylla</latin>
        <common>Blue-leaved wattle</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Fabaceae</family>
        <abstract>Acacia saligna, commonly known by various names including coojong, golden wreath
            wattle, orange wattle, blue-leafed wattle, Western Australian golden wattle, and, in
            Africa, Port Jackson willow, is a small tree in the family Fabaceae. Native to
            Australia, it is widely distributed throughout the south west corner of Western
            Australia, extending north as far as the Murchison River, and east to Israelite
            Bay.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Acacia_April_2015-3.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Acacia dealbata</latin>
        <common>Silver Wattle</common>
        <common>Mimosa</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree,shrub</tag>
        <tag>evergreen</tag>
        <family>Fabaceae</family>
        <abstract>Acacia dealbata (known as silver wattle, blue wattle or mimosa) is a species of
            Acacia, native to southeastern Australia in New South Wales, Victoria, Tasmania, and the
            Australian Capital Territory and widely introduced in Mediterranean, warm temperate, and
            highland tropical landscapes.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Acacia_dealbata-1.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Acer monspessulanum</latin>
        <common>Montpellier Maple</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree,shrub</tag>
        <tag>deciduous</tag>
        <family>Sapindaceae</family>
        <abstract>Acer monspessulanum (Montpellier maple) is a species of maple native to the
            Mediterranean region from Morocco and Portugal in the west, to Turkey, Syria, Lebanon,
            and Israel in the east, and north to the Jura Mountains in France and the Eifel in
            Germany.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Acer_monspessulanum_fg02.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Acer negundo</latin>
        <common>Box Elder</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Sapindaceae</family>
        <abstract>Acer negundo is a species of maple native to North America. Box elder, boxelder
            maple, ash-leaved maple, and maple ash are its most common names in the United States;
            in Britain and Ireland it is also known as ashleaf maple.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Acnegundo.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Albizia julibrissin</latin>
        <common>Persian Silk Tree</common>
        <common>Persian Acacia</common>
        <vedel/>
        <myphotos>silktree</myphotos>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <tag>deciduous</tag>
        <family>Fabaceae</family>
        <abstract>Albizia julibrissin (Persian silk tree, pink silk tree) is a species of tree in
            the family Fabaceae, native to southwestern and eastern Asia. The genus is named after
            the Italian nobleman Filippo degli Albizzi, who introduced it to Europe in the mid-18th
            century, and it is sometimes incorrectly spelled Albizzia. The specific epithet
            julibrissin is a corruption of the Persian word gul-i abrisham (گل ابریشم) which means
            "silk flower" (from gul گل "flower" + abrisham ابریشم "silk").</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/20130801Seidenbaum_Hockenheim01_crop.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Ailanthus altissima</latin>
        <common>Tree of Heaven</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Simaroubaceae</family>
        <abstract>Ailanthus altissima /eɪˈlænθəs ælˈtɪsᵻmə/, commonly known as tree of heaven,
            ailanthus, or in Standard Chinese as chouchun (Chinese: 臭椿; pinyin: chòuchūn; literally:
            "foul smelling tree"), is a deciduous tree in the Simaroubaceae family. It is native to
            both northeast and central China, as well as Taiwan. Unlike other members of the genus
            Ailanthus, it is found in temperate climates rather than the tropics. The tree grows
            rapidly and is capable of reaching heights of 15 metres (49 ft) in 25 years. However,
            the species is also short lived and rarely lives more than 50 years, though its
            remarkable suckering ability makes it possible for this tree to clone itself
            indefinitely and live considerably longer (since they are linked to the mother tree and
            thus partly fed by it, the suckers are less vulnerable than the seedlings and can grow
            faster). In China, the tree of heaven has a long and rich history. It was mentioned in
            the oldest extant Chinese dictionary and listed in countless Chinese medical texts for
            its purported ability to cure ailments ranging from mental illness to baldness. The
            roots, leaves and bark are still used today in traditional Chinese medicine, primarily
            as an astringent. The tree has been grown extensively both in China and abroad as a host
            plant for the ailanthus silkmoth, a moth involved in silk production. Ailanthus has
            become a part of western culture as well, with the tree serving as the central metaphor
            and subject matter of the best-selling American novel A Tree Grows in Brooklyn by Betty
            Smith. The tree was first brought from China to Europe in the 1740s and to the United
            States in 1784. It was one of the first trees brought west during a time when
            chinoiserie was dominating European arts, and was initially hailed as a beautiful garden
            specimen. However, enthusiasm soon waned after gardeners became familiar with its
            suckering habits and its foul smelling odour. Despite this, it was used extensively as a
            street tree during much of the 19th century. Outside Europe and the United States the
            plant has been spread to many other areas beyond its native range. In a number of these,
            it has become an invasive species due to its ability both to colonise disturbed areas
            quickly and to suppress competition with allelopathic chemicals. It is considered a
            noxious weed in Australia, the United States, New Zealand and many countries of central,
            eastern and southern Europe. The tree also resprouts vigorously when cut, making its
            eradication difficult and time-consuming. In many urban areas, it has acquired the
            derisive nicknames of "ghetto palm", "stink tree", and "tree of Hell".</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Götterbaum_(Ailanthus_altissima).jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Araucaria araucana</latin>
        <common>Monkey Puzzle</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Araucariaceae</family>
        <abstract>Araucaria araucana (commonly called the monkey puzzle tree, monkey tail tree,
            Chilean pine, or pehuén) is an evergreen tree growing to 1-1.5 m (3–5 ft) in diameter
            and 30–40 m (100–130 ft) in height. It is native to central and southern Chile and
            western Argentina. Araucaria araucana is the hardiest species in the conifer genus
            Araucaria. Because of the longevity of this species, it is described as a living fossil.
            It is also the national tree of Chile. Its conservation status was changed to Endangered
            by the IUCN in 2013 due to the dwindling population.</abstract>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Araucaria heterophylla</latin>
        <common>Norfolk Island Pine</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Araucariaceae</family>
        <abstract>Araucaria heterophylla (synonym A. excelsa) is a member of the ancient and now
            disjointly distributed family Araucariaceae. As its vernacular name Norfolk Island pine
            implies, the tree is endemic to Norfolk Island, a small island in the Pacific Ocean
            between New Zealand and New Caledonia, about 1440km east of Sydney, Australia. The genus
            Araucaria occurs across the South Pacific, especially concentrated in New Caledonia
            (about 700 km due north of Norfolk Island) where 13 closely related and
            similar-appearing species are found. It is sometimes called a star pine, triangle tree
            or living Christmas tree, due to its symmetrical shape as a sapling, although it is not
            a true pine.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Norfolk-Island-Pines.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Arbutus andrachne</latin>
        <common>Eastern Strawberry Tree</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Ericaceae</family>
        <abstract>Arbutus andrachne, commonly called the Greek strawberry tree, is an evergreen
            shrub or small tree in the family Ericaceae, native to the Mediterranean region, the
            Middle East, and southwestern Asia.</abstract>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Arbutus unedo</latin>
        <common>Strawberry Tree</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Ericaceae</family>
        <abstract>Arbutus unedo (strawberry tree) is an evergreen shrub or small tree in the family
            Ericaceae, native to the Mediterranean region and western Europe north to western France
            and Ireland. Due to its presence in southwest and northwest Ireland, it is known as
            either "Irish strawberry tree", or cain or cane apple (from the Gaelic name for the
            tree, caithne), or sometimes "Killarney strawberry tree".</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Arbutus_unedo_fruit_close-up.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Aucuba japonica</latin>
        <common>Aucuba</common>
        <common>Spotted Laurel</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>shrub</tag>
        <tag>dioecious</tag>
        <family>Garryaceae</family>
        <abstract>Aucuba japonica, commonly called spotted laurel, Japanese laurel, Japanese aucuba
            or gold dust plant (U.S.), is a shrub (1–5 m, 3.3–16.4 ft) native to rich forest soils
            of moist valleys, thickets, by streams and near shaded moist rocks in China, Korea, and
            Japan. This is the species of Aucuba commonly seen in gardens - often in variegated
            form. The leaves are opposite, broad lanceolate, 5–8 cm (2.0–3.1 in) long and 2–5 cm
            (0.79–1.97 in) wide. Aucuba japonica are dioecious, they have separate male and female
            plants. The flowers are small, 4–8 mm (0.16–0.31 in) diameter, with four purplish-brown
            petals; they are produced in clusters of 10-30 in a loose cyme. The fruit is a red berry
            approximately 1 cm (0.39 in) in diameter, which is avoided by birds.</abstract>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Bougainvillea</latin>
        <common>Bougainvillea</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>climber</tag>
        <family>Nyctaginaceae</family>
        <abstract>Bougainvillea (/ˌbuːɡᵻnˈvɪliə/ or /ˌboʊɡᵻnˈvɪliə/) is a genus of thorny ornamental
            vines, bushes, and trees with flower-like spring leaves near its flowers. Different
            authors accept between four and 18 species in the genus. They are native plants of South
            America from Brazil west to Peru and south to southern Argentina (Chubut Province).
            Bougainvillea are also known as buganvilla (Spain), bugambilia (Mexico, Guatemala, Cuba,
            Philippines), pokok bunga kertas (Indonesia), "'bougenville"' (Pakistan), Napoleón
            (Honduras), veranera (Colombia, Nicaragua, El Salvador, Costa Rica and Panama),
            trinitaria (Colombia, Panama, Puerto Rico, Dominican Republic &amp; Venezuela), Santa
            Rita (Argentina, Bolivia, Brazil, Paraguay and Uruguay) or papelillo (northern Peru).
            The vine species grow anywhere from 1 to 12 m (3 to 40 ft.) tall, scrambling over other
            plants with their spiky thorns. The thorns are tipped with a black, waxy substance. They
            are evergreen where rainfall occurs all year, or deciduous if there is a dry season. The
            leaves are alternate, simple ovate-acuminate, 4–13 cm long and 2–6 cm broad. The actual
            flower of the plant is small and generally white, but each cluster of three flowers is
            surrounded by three or six bracts with the bright colours associated with the plant,
            including pink, magenta, purple, red, orange, white, or yellow. Bougainvillea glabra is
            sometimes referred to as "paper flower" because the bracts are thin and papery. The
            fruit is a narrow five-lobed achene. Bougainvillea are relatively pest-free plants, but
            they may suffer from worms, snails and aphids. The larvae of some Lepidoptera species
            also use them as food plants, for example the giant leopard moth (Hypercompe
            scribonia).</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Bougainvillea_Flower.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Caesalpinia pulcherrima</latin>
        <common>Barbados Pride</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>shrub</tag>
        <family>Fabaceae</family>
        <abstract>Caesalpinia pulcherrima is a species of flowering plant in the pea family,
            Fabaceae, that is native to the tropics and subtropics of the Americas. It could be
            native to the West Indies, but its exact origin is unknown due to widespread
            cultivation. Common names for this species include poinciana, peacock flower, red bird
            of paradise, Mexican bird of paradise, dwarf poinciana, pride of Barbados, and
            flamboyant-de-jardin. The Hawaiian name for this plant is ʻOhai Aliʻi.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Caesalpinia_pulcherrima.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Melaleuca citrina</latin>
        <latin>Callistemon citrinus</latin>
        <common>Bottle brush</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>shrub</tag>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Myrtaceae</family>
        <abstract>Melaleuca citrina, commonly known as common red, crimson or lemon bottlebrush, is a plant in the myrtle family, Myrtaceae and is endemic to New South Wales and Victoria in Australia. It is a hardy and adaptable species, common in its natural habitat. It is widely cultivated, not only in Australia, often as a species of Callistemon. It was one of the first Australian plants to be grown outside the country, having been taken to England in 1770 by Joseph Banks. Its showy red flower spikes, present over most of the year in an ideal situation, account for its popularity.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Red_bottle_brush.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Camellia japonica</latin>
        <common>Camellia</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>shrub</tag>
        <family>Theaceae</family>
        <abstract>Camellia japonica (the Japanese camellia) is one of the best known species of the
            genus Camellia. Sometimes called the Rose of winter, it belongs to the Theaceae family.
            It is the official state flower of Alabama. There are thousands of cultivars of C.
            japonica in cultivation, with many different colors and forms of flowers. In the wild,
            it is found in mainland China (Shandong, east Zhejiang), Taiwan, southern Korea and
            southern Japan. It grows in forests, at altitudes of around 300–1,100 metres (980–3,610
            ft).</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Camellia_japonica-IMG_2051.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Campsis radicans</latin>
        <common>Trumpet Vine</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>climber</tag>
        <family>Bignoniaceae</family>
        <abstract>Campsis radicans (trumpet vine or trumpet creeper, also known in North America as
            cow itch vine or hummingbird vine), is a species of flowering plant of the family
            Bignoniaceae, native to the eastern United States and naturalized in parts of the
            western United States as well as in Ontario, parts of Europe, and scattered locations in
            Latin America. Growing to 10 m (33 ft), it is a vigorous, deciduous woody vine, notable
            for its showy trumpet-shaped flowers. It inhabits woodlands and riverbanks, and is also
            a popular garden subject.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Campsis_radicans-600px.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Cassia</latin>
        <common>Cassia</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family/>
        <abstract/>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Castanea sativa</latin>
        <common>Sweet Chestnut</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Fagaceae</family>
        <abstract>Castanea sativa, or sweet chestnut, is a species of flowering plant in the family
            Fagaceae, native to Europe and Asia Minor, and widely cultivated throughout the
            temperate world. A substantial, long-lived deciduous tree, it produces an edible seed,
            the chestnut, which has been used in cooking since ancient times.</abstract>
        <picture>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Chestnuts.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Casuarina equisetifolia</latin>
        <common>She-oak</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Casuarinaceae</family>
        <abstract>Casuarina equisetifolia or Australian pine tree is a she-oak species of the genus
            Casuarina. The native range extends from Burma and Vietnam throughout Malaysia east to
            French Polynesia, New Caledonia, and Vanuatu, and south to Australia (north of Northern
            Territory, north and east Queensland, and north-eastern New South Wales). Populations
            are also found in Madagascar, but it is doubtful if this is within the native range of
            the species. The species has been introduced to the Southern United States and West
            Africa. It is an invasive species in Florida and South Africa.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Casuarina_equesitifolia_tree.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Catalpa bignonioides</latin>
        <common>Indian Bean Tree</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Bignoniaceae</family>
        <abstract>Catalpa bignonioides is a species of Catalpa that is native to the southeastern
            United States in Alabama, Florida, Georgia, Louisiana, and Mississippi. Common names
            include southern catalpa, cigartree, and Indian-bean-tree.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Catalpa_bignonioides_inflorescence.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Cedrus atlantica</latin>
        <common>Altas Cedar</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Pinaceae</family>
        <abstract>Cedrus atlantica, the Atlas cedar, is a cedar native to the Atlas Mountains of
            Morocco (Middle Atlas, High Atlas), to the Rif, and to the Tell Atlas in Algeria. A
            majority of the modern sources treat it as a distinct species Cedrus atlantica, but some
            sources consider it a subspecies of Lebanon cedar (C. libani subsp.
            atlantica).</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Cedrus_atlantica.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Cedrus deodara</latin>
        <common>Deodar</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Pinaceae</family>
        <abstract>Cedrus deodara (deodar cedar, Himalayan cedar, or deodar/devdar/devadar/devadaru;
            Sanskrit देवदारु devadāru, Hindi: देवदार devadār, दारूक dāruk; Urdu: ديودار/ دیار
            deodār; Kannada:ದೇವಧಾರ Chinese: 雪松 xuě sōng) is a species of cedar native to the western
            Himalayas in eastern Afghanistan, northern Pakistan (especially in Khyber Pakhtunkhwa)
            and India (Jammu and Kashmir, Himachal Pradesh, Sikkim, Darjeeling and Uttarakhand
            states), southwesternmost Tibet in (China) and western Nepal, occurring at 1,500–3,200 m
            (4,921–10,499 ft) altitude. It is a large evergreen coniferous tree reaching 40–50 m
            (131–164 ft) tall, exceptionally 60 m (197 ft) with a trunk up to 3 m (10 ft) in
            diameter. It has a conic crown with level branches and drooping branchlets. The leaves
            are needle-like, mostly 2.5–5 cm (0.98–1.97 in) long, occasionally up to 7 cm (2.8 in)
            long, slender (1 mm (0.039 in) thick), borne singly on long shoots, and in dense
            clusters of 20–30 on short shoots; they vary from bright green to glaucous blue-green in
            colour. The female cones are barrel-shaped, 7–13 cm (2.8–5.1 in) long and 5–9 cm
            (2.0–3.5 in) broad, and disintegrate when mature (in 12 months) to release the winged
            seeds. The male cones are 4–6 cm (1.6–2.4 in) long, and shed their pollen in
            autumn.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Cedrus_deodara_Manali_2.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Cedrus libani</latin>
        <common>Cedar of Lebanon</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Pinaceae</family>
        <abstract>Cedrus libani is a species of cedar native to the mountains of the Mediterranean
            region.</abstract>
        <picture>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Libanonzeder.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Celtis australis</latin>
        <common>Southern Nettle Tree</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Cannabaceae</family>
        <abstract>Celtis australis, commonly known as the European nettle tree, Mediterranean
            hackberry, lote tree, or honeyberry, is a deciduous tree native to southern Europe,
            North Africa, and Asia Minor. The tree was introduced to England in 1796.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Illustration_Celtis_australis0.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Ceratonia siliqua</latin>
        <common>Carob</common>
        <common>Locust Tree</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Fabaceae</family>
        <abstract>Ceratonia siliqua, commonly known as the carob tree, St John's-bread, or locust
            bean (not to be confused with the African locust bean) is a species of flowering
            evergreen shrub or tree in the pea family, Fabaceae. It is widely cultivated for its
            edible pods, and as an ornamental tree in gardens. The ripe, dried pod is often ground
            to carob powder, which is used to replace cocoa powder. Carob bars, an alternative to
            chocolate bars, are often available in health-food stores. The carob tree is native to
            the Mediterranean region, including Southern Europe, Northern Africa, the larger
            Mediterranean islands, the Levant and Middle-East of Western Asia into Iran; and the
            Canary Islands and Macaronesia. The carat, a unit of mass for gemstones, and of purity
            for gold, takes its name, indirectly, from the Greek word for a carob seed,
            kerátion.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Illustration_Ceratonia_siliqua0.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Cercis siliquastrum</latin>
        <common>Judas Tree</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Fabaceae</family>
        <abstract>Cercis siliquastrum, commonly known as the Judas tree or Judas-tree, is a small
            deciduous tree from Southern Europe and Western Asia which is noted for its prolific
            display of deep pink flowers in spring.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/PikiWiki_Israel_3421_Geography_of_Israel.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Cestrum parqui</latin>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>shrub</tag>
        <family>Solanaceae</family>
        <abstract>Cestrum parqui, commonly known as green cestrum, green poison berry, Chilean
            cestrum or willow-leaved jessamine, and is sometimes incorrectly referred to as deadly
            nightshade, is a species of flowering plant in the family Solanaceae that is native to
            central and South America. It is an upright, straggly, woody deciduous or semi-evergreen
            shrub 2–3 metres (6 ft 7 in–9 ft 10 in) tall with one or more brittle green stems. Light
            green leaves are alternate and shiny green to 12 cm (5 in) long, giving off a foul
            rubbery smell when crushed. It has sprays of small, fragrant, tubular yellow-green
            flowers approximately 2.5 cm long on the ends of the stems, flowering from late spring
            to autumn. These produce clusters of small, black egg shaped berries during summer to
            autumn. Green cestrum is highly attractive to birds, and seedlings are often found
            growing under perching trees, along fence lines and on creek banks. It is also dispersed
            by water. Spread by birds, it invades gardens, rural lands and bushland. It has a deep
            and persistent taproot. This weed is considered a major problem because of its toxicity
            to livestock (especially cattle) and poultry which eat green cestrum when there is a
            shortage of other feed. All parts of the plant material, stems, leaves, berries and even
            partly burnt roots pose a serious threat to livestock. Death is usually rapid and
            painful. The plant is also known to be toxic to other livestock and humans. This species
            is defined as a noxious plant in New South Wales under the Noxious Weeds Act 1993 and
            all plants must be destroyed. In cultivation in the United Kingdom, this plant has
            gained the Royal Horticultural Society's Award of Garden Merit.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Cestrum_parqui.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Chamaerops humilis</latin>
        <common>Dwarf Fan Palm</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>palm</tag>
        <family>Arecaceae</family>
        <abstract>Chamaerops is a genus of flowering plants in the palm family Arecaceae. The only
            currently fully accepted species is Chamaerops humilis, variously called European fan
            palm, or the Mediterranean dwarf palm. It is one of the more cold-hardy palms used in
            landscaping in temperate climates.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Chamaerops_humilis_(Zingaro)015.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Cistus albidus</latin>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>shrub</tag>
        <family>Cistaceae</family>
        <abstract>Cistus albidus, the grey-leaved cistus, is a shrubby species of flowering plant in
            the family Cistaceae, with pink to purple flowers, native to south-western Europe and
            western north Africa.</abstract>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Cistus ladanifer</latin>
        <common>Gum cistus</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>shrub</tag>
        <family>Cistaceae</family>
        <abstract>Cistus ladanifer is a species of flowering plant in the family Cistaceae. It is
            native to the western Mediterranean region. Common names include gum rockrose, laudanum,
            labdanum, common gum cistus, and brown-eyed rockrose. It is a shrub growing 1–2.5 m (3
            ft 3 in–8 ft 2 in) tall and wide. The leaves are evergreen, lanceolate, 3–10 cm long and
            1–2 cm broad, dark green above and paler underneath. The flowers are 5–8 cm diameter,
            with 5 papery white petals, usually with a red to maroon spot at the base, surrounding
            the yellow stamens and pistils. The whole plant is covered with the sticky exudate of
            fragrant resin, the source of labdanum, used in herbal medicine and perfumery. C.
            ladanifer is particularly well suited to the Continentalized Mediterranean climate,
            standing both long summer droughts and cold weather. It is an extremely aggressive plant
            which has taken over much of former farmland and grasslands in the mountain regions of
            central Spain and much of southern Portugal. In Spanish it is known as Jara pringosa
            meaning "sticky shrub". In Portuguese it is known as "esteva". It has been found to have
            mycorrhizal associations with Boletus edulis, Boletus rhodoxanthus, and Laccaria
            laccata.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Cistus_May_2014-9.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Cistus monspeliensis</latin>
        <common>Sun Rose</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>shrub</tag>
        <family>Cistaceae</family>
        <abstract>Cistus monspeliensis is a species of rockrose known by the common name Montpellier
            cistus. It is native to southern Europe and northern Africa, in the Mediterranean
            forests, woodlands, and scrub ecosystems of matorral—maquis shrublands.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Cistus_monspeliensis_(Puntagorda)_01.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Citrus</latin>
        <common>Citrus</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Aurantioideae</family>
        <abstract>Citrus is a genus of flowering trees and shrubs in the rue family, Rutaceae.
            Plants in the genus produce citrus fruits, including important crops like oranges,
            lemons, grapefruit, and limes. The most recent research indicates an origin in
            Australia, New Caledonia and New Guinea. Some researchers believe that the origin is in
            the part of Southeast Asia bordered by Northeast India, Burma (Myanmar) and the Yunnan
            province of China, and it is in this region that some commercial species such as
            oranges, mandarins, and lemons originated. Citrus fruit has been cultivated in an
            ever-widening area since ancient times.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/OrangeBloss_wb.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Citrus aurantium</latin>
        <common>Citrus</common>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Rutaceae</family>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Clematis cirrhosa</latin>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>climber</tag>
        <family>Ranunculaceae</family>
        <abstract>Clematis cirrhosa is a species of flowering plants in the Ranunculaceae. It
            includes the 'Freckles', 'Wisley Cream' and 'Jingle Bells' cultivars. It is also one of
            8 subdivisions in the Thorncroft Clematis catalogue, published in 2000.</abstract>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Clematis flammula</latin>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>climber</tag>
        <family>Ranunculaceae</family>
        <abstract>Clematis flammula is a temperate liana known by the common name fragrant virgin's
            bower. It is native to southern Europe and northern Africa, but it is cultivated
            worldwide as an ornamental plant in gardens. The woody vine bears fragrant white flowers
            and small green achenes. When the flowers are newly opened they have a strong sweet
            almond fragrance. The vine grows in a tangled mass that is heavily sprinkled with
            flowers throughout the warmer months. It is popular with gardeners as a decoration along
            fences and trellises, or as ground cover. If the vine has no other plants or structures
            to climb on, it will climb on itself, forming a large, densely tangled bush. The plant
            sends out many shoots and can reach over five metres in height. It is sweet-smelling but
            poisonous. In some areas, this species has become a nuisance after its introduction. It
            is a weed outside of gardens and landscaped areas. Clematis flammula var. maritima is a
            hardier variety that is adapted to sand dunes. It is currently being studied as an agent
            of soil stabilization on eroded sandy beaches.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Clematis_flamula_flor.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Cotinus coggygria</latin>
        <common>Wig Tree</common>
        <common>Smoke Tree</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>shrub</tag>
        <family>Anacardiaceae</family>
        <abstract>Cotinus coggygria, syn. Rhus cotinus, the European smoketree, Eurasian smoketree,
            smoke tree, smoke bush, or dyer's sumach is a species of flowering plant in the family
            Anacardiaceae, native to a large area from southern Europe, east across central Asia and
            the Himalayas to northern China. It is a multiple-branching shrub growing to 5–7 m
            (16–23 ft) tall with an open, spreading, irregular habit, only rarely forming a small
            tree. The leaves are 3-8 cm long rounded ovals, green with a waxy glaucous sheen. The
            autumn colour can be strikingly varied, from peach and yellow to scarlet. The flowers
            are numerous, produced in large inflorescences 15–30 cm (5.9–11.8 in) long; each flower
            5-10 mm diameter, with five pale yellow petals. Most of the flowers in each
            inflorescence abort, elongating into yellowish-pink to pinkish-purple feathery plumes
            (when viewed en masse these have a wispy 'smoke-like' appearance, hence the common name)
            which surround the small (2-3 mm) drupaceous fruit that do develop.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Cotinus_coggygria5.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Crataegus azarolus</latin>
        <common>Azarole</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Rosaceae</family>
        <abstract>Crataegus azarolus is a species of hawthorn known by the common names azarole,
            azerole, and Mediterranean medlar. It is native to the Mediterranean Basin and is a
            common plant there, growing on sites comparable to those the European common hawthorn
            grows on. In the Arabic-speaking countries it is the commonest of the hawthorn species;
            in the Arabic language the term "common hawthorn" means the azarole hawthorn. When
            growing in the wild the azerole bears plentiful crops of haw fruits, which are similar
            to the haws of the European common hawthorn, but plumper. C. azarolus is often divided
            into subspecies or varieties, for example Christensen in his monograph uses four
            varieties: * C. azarolus var. azarolus has orange fruit. * C. azarolus var. aronia L.,
            has yellowish fruit often with some red tinges * C. azarolus var. chlorocarpa (Moris)
            K.I.Chr. has yellowish fruit * C. azarolus var. pontica (K.Koch) K.I.Chr. has yellowish
            or orange fruit C. azarolus has been used historically for a number of medicinal
            purposes.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Crataegus_azarolus_HRM.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Cupressus sempervirens</latin>
        <common>Italian Cypress</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Cupressaceae</family>
        <abstract>Cupressus sempervirens, the Mediterranean cypress (also known as Italian cypress,
            Tuscan cypress, graveyard cypress, or pencil pine), is a species of cypress native to
            the eastern Mediterranean region, in northeast Libya, southern Albania, southern coastal
            Croatia (Dalmatia), southern Greece, southern Turkey, Cyprus, northern Egypt, western
            Syria, Lebanon, Israel, Malta, Italy, western Jordan, and also a disjunct population in
            Iran. C. sempervirens is a medium-sized coniferous evergreen tree to 35 m (115 ft) tall,
            with a conic crown with level branches and variably loosely hanging branchlets. It is
            very long-lived, with some trees reported to be over 1,000 years old. The foliage grows
            in dense sprays, dark green in colour. The leaves are scale-like, 2–5 mm long, and
            produced on rounded (not flattened) shoots. The seed cones are ovoid or oblong, 25–40 mm
            long, with 10-14 scales, green at first, maturing brown about 20–24 months after
            pollination. The male cones are 3–5 mm long, and release pollen in late winter. It is
            moderately susceptible to cypress canker, caused by the fungus Seiridium cardinale, and
            can suffer extensive dieback where this disease is common. The species name sempervirens
            comes from the Latin for 'evergreen'.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Med_Cypress.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Cytisus scoparius</latin>
        <common>Common Broom</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>shrub</tag>
        <family>Fabaceae</family>
        <abstract>Cytisus scoparius, the common broom or Scotch broom, syn. Sarothamnus scoparius,
            is a perennial leguminous shrub native to western and central Europe. In Britain and
            Ireland, the standard name is broom, but this name is also used for other members of the
            Genisteae tribe, such as French broom or Spanish broom, and the term common broom is
            sometimes used for clarification. In other English-speaking countries, the most
            prevalent common name is Scotch broom (or Scot's broom); English broom is also
            occasionally used.</abstract>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Datura stramonium</latin>
        <common>Thorn apple</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>shrub</tag>
        <family>Solanaceae</family>
        <abstract>Datura stramonium, known by the common names Jimson weed or Devil's snare, is a
            plant in the nightshade family. It is believed to have originated in Mexico, but has now
            become naturalized in many other regions. Other common names for D. stramonium include
            thornapple and moon flower, and it has the Spanish name toloache. Other names for the
            plant include hell's bells,devil’s trumpet, devil’s weed, tolguacha, Jamestown weed,
            stinkweed, locoweed, pricklyburr, and devil’s cucumber. Datura has been used in
            traditional medicine to relieve asthma symptoms and as an analgesic during surgery or
            bonesetting. It is also a powerful hallucinogen and deliriant, which is used spiritually
            for the intense visions it produces. However, the tropane alkaloids responsible for both
            the medicinal and hallucinogenic properties are fatally toxic in only slightly higher
            amounts than the medicinal dosage, and careless use often results in hospitalizations
            and deaths.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/DaturaMetel-plant.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Delonix regia</latin>
        <common>Flamboyant</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Caesalpinioideae</family>
        <abstract>Delonix regia is a species of flowering plant in the bean family Fabaceae,
            subfamily Caesalpinioideae. It is noted for its fern-like leaves and flamboyant display
            of flowers. In many tropical parts of the world it is grown as an ornamental tree and in
            English it is given the name royal poinciana or flamboyant. It is also one of several
            trees known as Flame tree. This species was previously placed in the genus Poinciana,
            named for Phillippe de Longvilliers de Poincy, the 17th century governor of Saint
            Christophe (Saint Kitts). It is a non nodulating legume.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Royal_Poinciana.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Diospyros kaki</latin>
        <common>Persimmon</common>
        <vedel/>
        <myphotos>persimon</myphotos>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Ebenaceae</family>
        <abstract>Diospyros kaki is the most widely cultivated species of the genus Diospyros.
            Although its first published botanical description was not until 1780, the kaki is among
            the oldest plants in cultivation, known for its use in China for more than 2000 years.
            In some rural Chinese communities, the kaki fruit is seen as having a great mystical
            power that can be harnessed to solve headaches, back pains and foot ache. The persimmon
            (kaki) is a sweet, slightly tangy fruit with a soft to occasionally fibrous texture.
            This species, native to China, is deciduous, with broad, stiff leaves. Cultivation
            extended first to other parts of East Asia and was later introduced to California and
            southern Europe in the 19th century, to Brazil in the 1890s, and numerous cultivars have
            been selected. A variety is Diospyros kaki var. sylvestris Makino.When ripe, this fruit
            comprises thick pulpy jelly encased in a waxy thin-skinned shell. In many cultivars,
            known as the astringent varieties, the fruit has a high proanthocyanidin-type tannin
            content which makes the immature fruit astringent and bitter. The tannin levels are
            reduced as the fruit matures. It is not edible in its crisp, firm state; it tastes best
            when allowed to rest and soften after harvest. It has a soft jelly-like consistency and
            is best eaten with a spoon. The Japanese 'Hachiya' is a widely grown astringent
            cultivar. Other cultivars, such as Fuyu, do not contain tannins when firm. They can be
            eaten like an apple or can be allowed to go to any stage of ripeness, including to the
            jelly-like stage. These non-astringent varieties are considered to have a less complex
            flavor. "Sharon Fruit" (named originally after Sharon plain in Israel) is the trade name
            for non-astringent D. kaki fruit.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Kaki_20041002.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Diospyros lotus</latin>
        <common>Date Plum</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Ebenaceae</family>
        <abstract>Diospyros lotus, with common names date-plum, Caucasian persimmon, or lilac
            persimmon, is a widely cultivated species of the genus Diospyros, native to subtropical
            southwest Asia and southeast Europe. Its English name derives from the small fruit,
            which have a taste reminiscent of both plums and dates. It is among the oldest plants in
            cultivation.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Diospyros_lotus_01.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Dracaena draco</latin>
        <common>Canarian Dragon Tree</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Asparagaceae</family>
        <abstract>Not to be confused with the related Dracaena cinnabari, the dragon blood tree
            native to Socotra (an island near Yemen). Dracaena draco, the Canary Islands dragon tree
            or drago, is a subtropical tree-like plant in the genus Dracaena, native to the Canary
            Islands, Cape Verde, Madeira, and locally in western Morocco, and introduced to the
            Azores. It is the natural symbol of the island of Tenerife, together with the blue
            chaffinch.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Dracaena_draco.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Elaeagnus angustifolia</latin>
        <common>Oleaster</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>shrub</tag>
        <family>Elaeagnaceae</family>
        <abstract>Elaeagnus angustifolia, commonly called Russian olive, silver berry, oleaster,
            Persian olive, or wild olive, or commonly referred to as senjid or sinjid in Afghanistan
            and senjed in Iran, is a species of Elaeagnus, native to western and central Asia,
            Afghanistan, from southern Russia and Kazakhstan to Turkey and Iran. It is now also
            widely established in North America as an introduced species.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Russian_Olive.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Ephedra fragilis</latin>
        <common>Joint Pine</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>shrub</tag>
        <family>Ephedra_(genus)</family>
        <abstract>Ephedra fragilis, commonly named the joint pine, is a species of Ephedra that is
            native to eastern Mediterranean region of southern Europe and Northern Africa, and from
            Madeira and the Canary Islands in the Atlantic. Its habitats are rocky hills and stone
            walls, where it grows to 6 feet (1.8 m) tall.</abstract>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Erica arborea</latin>
        <common>Tree Heather</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>shrub</tag>
        <family>Ericaceae</family>
        <abstract>Erica arborea (tree heath) is a species of flowering plant (angiosperms) in the
            heather family, Ericaceae. There are disjunct populations in Africa including the
            Ethiopian Highlands, the mountains of Ruwenzori and the Cameroon Mountains. In Africa it
            is normally referred to as giant heather. It is native to the maquis shrublands
            surrounding the Mediterranean Basin and west to Portugal and the Canary and Madeira
            Islands. Naturalised populations occur in south-eastern Australia.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Erica_arborea_JPG1.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Eriobotrya japonica</latin>
        <common>Loquat</common>
        <vedel/>
        <myphotos>loquat</myphotos>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Rosaceae</family>
        <abstract>The loquat (Eriobotrya japonica) is a species of flowering plant in the family
            Rosaceae, an ancient fruit grown in Japan for the past 1,000 years which is probably
            native to the cooler hill regions of China to south-central China. It is a large
            evergreen shrub or tree, grown commercially for its yellow fruit, and also cultivated as
            an ornamental plant. Eriobotrya japonica was formerly thought to be closely related to
            the genus Mespilus, and is still sometimes known as the Japanese medlar. It is also
            known as Japanese plum and Chinese plum, also known as pipa in China.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Loquat-0.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Erythrina crista-galli</latin>
        <common>Coral Tree</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Fabaceae</family>
        <abstract>Erythrina crista-galli, often known as the cockspur coral tree, is a flowering
            tree in the family Fabaceae, native to Argentina, Uruguay, southern Brazil and Paraguay.
            It is widely planted as a street or garden tree in other countries, notably in
            California. It is known by several common names within South America: ceibo, seíbo
            (Spanish), corticeira (Portuguese) and the more ambiguous bucaré, to name a few. Its
            specific epithet crista-galli means "cock's comb" in Latin. The ceibo is the national
            tree of Argentina, and its flower the national flower of Argentina and Uruguay. This
            species characteristically grows wild in gallery forest ecosystems along watercourses,
            as well as in swamps and wetlands. In urban settings, it is often planted in parks for
            its bright red flowers.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Erythrina_crista-galli.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Eucalyptus robusta</latin>
        <common>Swamp Mahogony</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Myrtaceae</family>
        <abstract>Eucalyptus robusta, commonly known as swamp mahogany or swamp messmate, is a tree
            native to eastern Australia. Growing in swampy or waterlogged soils, it is up to 30 m
            (100 ft) high with thick spongy reddish brown bark and dark green broad leaves, which
            help form a dense canopy. The white to cream flowers appear in autumn and winter. The
            leaves are commonly eaten by insects, and are a food item for the koala. It is an
            important winter-flowering species in eastern Australia, and has been planted
            extensively in many countries around the world. Its timber is used for firewood and in
            general construction.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Eucalyptus_robusta_robson2.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Eucalyptus globulus</latin>
        <common>Tasmanian Blue Gum</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Myrtaceae</family>
        <abstract>Eucalyptus globulus, the Tasmanian bluegum, southern blue-gum or blue gum, is an
            evergreen tree, one of the most widely cultivated trees native to Australia. They
            typically grow from 30–55 m (98–180 ft) tall. The tallest currently known specimen in
            Tasmania is 90.7 m (298 ft) tall. There are historical claims of even taller trees, the
            tallest being 101 m (331 ft). The natural distribution of the species includes Tasmania
            and southern Victoria (particularly the Otway Ranges and southern Gippsland). There are
            also isolated occurrences on King Island and Flinders Island in Bass Strait and on the
            summit of the You Yangs near Geelong. There are naturalised non-native occurrences in
            Spain and Portugal, and other parts of southern Europe incl. Cyprus, southern Africa,
            New Zealand, western United States (California), Hawaii, Macaronesia, and the Caucasus
            (Western Georgia). The d'Entrecasteaux expedition made immediate use of the species when
            they discovered it, the timber being used to improve their oared boats. The Tasmanian
            blue gum was proclaimed as the floral emblem of Tasmania on 27 November 1962. The
            species name is from the Latin globulus, a little button, referring to the shape of the
            operculum.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Starr_031002-0027_Eucalyptus_globulus.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Euphorbia canariensis</latin>
        <common>Canary Island Spurge</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>shrub</tag>
        <tag>succulent</tag>
        <family>Euphorbiinae</family>
        <abstract>Euphorbia canariensis, commonly known as the Canary Island spurge, Hercules club
            or in Spanish cardón, is a succulent member of the genus Euphorbia and family
            Euphorbiaceae endemic to the Canary Islands. It is the plant symbol of the island of
            Gran Canaria.</abstract>
        <picture>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Euphorbia_canariensis_Tenerife_2012.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Euphorbia dendroides</latin>
        <common>Tree Spurge</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>shrub</tag>
        <family>Euphorbiaceae</family>
        <abstract>Euphorbia dendroides, also known as Tree Spurge, is a small tree of the
            Euphorbiaceae family that grows in semi-arid and mediterranean climates.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Euphorbia_dendroides3-Corsica~2011_04_30.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Euphorbia pulcherrima</latin>
        <common>Poinsettia</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Euphorbiaceae</family>
        <abstract>The poinsettia (/pɔɪnˈsɛtiə/ or /pɔɪnˈsɛtə/) (Euphorbia pulcherrima) is a
            commercially important plant species of the diverse spurge family. The species is
            indigenous to Mexico. It is particularly well known for its red and green foliage and is
            widely used in Christmas floral displays. It derives its common English name from Joel
            Roberts Poinsett, the first United States Minister to Mexico, who introduced the plant
            to the US in 1825.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Weihnachtsstern_-_groß.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Fraxinus ornus</latin>
        <common>Manna Ash</common>
        <common>Flowering Ash</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Oleaceae</family>
        <abstract>Fraxinus ornus (manna ash or South European flowering ash) is a species of
            Fraxinus native to southern Europe and southwestern Asia, from Spain and Italy north to
            Austria, Poland and the Czech Republic, and east through the Balkans, Turkey, and
            western Syria to Lebanon and Armenia.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Fraxinus_ornus_JPG2.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Ficus benghalensis</latin>
        <common>Banyan Tree</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Moraceae</family>
        <abstract>Ficus benghalensis, with the common name Indian banyan, is a tree which is native
            to the Indian Subcontinent. Specimens in India are among the largest trees in the world
            by canopy coverage.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Banyantree.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Ficus microcarpa</latin>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Moraceae</family>
        <abstract>Ficus microcarpa, also known as Chinese banyan, Malayan banyan, Indian laurel,
            curtain fig, or gajumaru (ガジュマル), is a tree in the fig family Moraceae. It is native in
            a range from China through tropical Asia and the Caroline Islands to Australia. It is
            widely planted as a shade tree and frequently misidentified as F. retusa or as F. nitida
            (F. benjamina).</abstract>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Ficus macrophylla</latin>
        <common>Morton Bay Fig</common>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Moraceae</family>
        <abstract>Ficus macrophylla, commonly known as the Moreton Bay fig or Australian banyan, is
            a large evergreen banyan tree of the family Moraceae native to eastern Australia, from
            the Wide Bay–Burnett region in the north to the Illawarra in New South Wales, as well as
            Lord Howe Island. Its common name is derived from Moreton Bay in Queensland, Australia.
            It is best known for its imposing buttress roots. As Ficus macrophylla is a strangler
            fig, seed germination usually takes place in the canopy of a host tree and the seedling
            lives as an epiphyte until its roots establish contact with the ground. It then enlarges
            and strangles its host, eventually becoming a freestanding tree by itself. Individuals
            may reach 60 m (200 ft) in height. The large leathery, dark green leaves are 15–30 cm
            (6–12 in) long. </abstract>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Ficus benjamina</latin>
        <common>Weeping Fig</common>
        <myphotos>ficus_benjamina</myphotos>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Moraceae</family>
        <abstract>Ficus benjamina, commonly known as weeping fig, benjamin fig or Ficus tree, and
            often sold in stores as just ficus, is a species of flowering plant in the family
            Moraceae, native to Asia and Australia. It is the official tree of Bangkok. The species
            is also naturalized in the West Indies and in the States of Florida and Arizona in the
            United States. Ficus benjamina is a tree reaching 30 metres (98 ft) tall in natural
            conditions, with gracefully drooping branchlets and glossy leaves 6–13 cm (2–5 in), oval
            with an acuminate tip. In its native range, its small fruit are favored by some birds,
            such as the superb fruit dove, wompoo fruit dove, pink-spotted fruit dove, ornate fruit
            dove, orange-bellied fruit dove, Torresian imperial pigeon, purple-tailed imperial
            pigeon (Frith et al. 1976).</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Ficus_benjamina2.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Ficus carica</latin>
        <common>Common fig</common>
        <vedel/>
        <myphotos>ficus_carica</myphotos>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Moraceae</family>
        <abstract>Ficus carica is an Asian species of flowering plants in the mulberry family, known
            as the common fig (or just the fig). It is the source of the fruit also called the fig,
            and as such is an important crop in those areas where it is grown commercially. Native
            to the Middle East and western Asia, it has been sought out and cultivated since ancient
            times, and is now widely grown throughout the world, both for its fruit and as an
            ornamental plant. The species has become naturalized in scattered locations in Asia and
            North America.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/58571_Ficus_carica_L.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Ficus elastica</latin>
        <common>Indian Rubber Tree</common>
        <vedel/>
        <myphotos>ficus_elastica</myphotos>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Moraceae</family>
        <abstract>Ficus elastica, the rubber fig, rubber bush, rubber tree, rubber plant, or Indian
            rubber bush, is a species of plant in the fig genus, native to northeast India, Nepal,
            Bhutan, Burma, China (Yunnan), Malaysia, and Indonesia. It has become naturalized in Sri
            Lanka, the West Indies, and the US State of Florida.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Ficus_November_2008-1.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Ficus sycamorus</latin>
        <common>Sycamore Fig</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Moraceae</family>
        <abstract>Ficus sycomorus (Bambara: Sutoro), called the sycamore fig or the fig-mulberry
            (because the leaves resemble those of the mulberry), sycamore, or sycomore, is a fig
            species that has been cultivated since ancient times. The term sycamore spelled with an
            A has been used for a variety of plants and is widely used in England to refer to the
            Great Maple, Acer pseudoplatanus. For clarity, the Ficus sycomorus species of fig is
            usually exclusively referred to as "sycomore", with an O rather than an A as the second
            vowel.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Sycomore_Fig_Tree_(Ficus_sycomorus)_(16707986040).jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Gardenia jasminoides</latin>
        <common>Gardinia</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>shrub</tag>
        <family>Rubiaceae</family>
        <abstract>Gardenia jasminoides, (gardenia, cape jasmine, cape jessamine, danh-danh, or
            jasmin) is an evergreen flowering plant of the family Rubiaceae. It originated in Asia
            and is most commonly found growing wild in Vietnam, Southern China, Taiwan, Japan,
            Myanmar, and India. With its shiny green leaves and heavily fragrant white summer
            flowers, it is widely used in gardens in warm temperate and subtropical climates, and as
            a houseplant in temperate regions. It has been in cultivation in China for at least a
            thousand years, and was introduced to English gardens in the mid 18th century. Many
            varieties have been bred for horticulture, with low growing, and large-and
            long-flowering forms.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Gardenia_jasminoides_cv1.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Gleditsia triacanthos</latin>
        <common>Honey Locust</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Fabaceae</family>
        <abstract>The honey locust (Gleditsia triacanthos) also known as the thorny locust, is a
            deciduous tree in the Fabaceae family, native to central North America where it is
            mostly found in the moist soil of river valleys ranging from southeastern South Dakota
            to New Orleans and central Texas, and as far east as eastern Massachusetts. The species
            has become a significant invasive weed in other regions of the world.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Gleditsia_triacanthos_Maryhill_Museum_01.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Hibiscus rosa-sinensis</latin>
        <common>Hibiscus</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>shrub</tag>
        <family>Malvaceae</family>
        <abstract>Hibiscus rosa-sinensis, known colloquially as Chinese hibiscus, China rose,
            Hawaiian hibiscus, and shoeblackplant, is a species of tropical hibiscus, a flowering
            plant in the Hibisceae tribe of the family Malvaceae, native to East Asia.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Hibiscus_Brilliant.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Hibiscus syriacus</latin>
        <common>Rose Mallow</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>shrub</tag>
        <family>Malvaceae</family>
        <abstract>Hibiscus syriacus is a species of flowering plant in the family Malvaceae, native
            to much of Asia (though not, as Linnaeus thought, Syria, in spite of the name he gave
            it). Common names include rose of Sharon (especially in North America), Syrian ketmia or
            rose mallow (United Kingdom) and St Joseph's rod (Italy).</abstract>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Hyphaene thebaica</latin>
        <common>Doum Palm</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>palm</tag>
        <family>Arecaceae</family>
        <abstract>Hyphaene thebaica, with common names doum palm (Ar: دوم) and gingerbread tree
            (also doom palm), is a type of palm tree with edible oval fruit. It is a native to the
            Arabian Peninsula and also to the northern half of Africa where it is widely distributed
            and tends to grow in places where groundwater is present. It has been shown that dietary
            supplementation with doum palm extract has hypotensive and hypolipidemic
            effects.</abstract>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Jacaranda mimosifolia</latin>
        <common>Jacaranda</common>
        <vedel/>
        <myphotos>jacaranda</myphotos>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Bignoniaceae</family>
        <abstract>Jacaranda mimosifolia is a sub-tropical tree native to south-central South America
            that has been widely planted elsewhere because of its beautiful and long-lasting blue
            flowers. It is also known as jacaranda, blue jacaranda, black poui, or as the fern tree.
            Older sources call it Jacaranda acutifolia, but it is nowadays more usually classified
            as Jacaranda mimosifolia. In scientific usage, the name "Jacaranda" refers to the genus
            Jacaranda, which has many other members, but in horticultural and everyday usage, it
            nearly always means the blue jacaranda.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Jacaranda_mimosifolia_flowers_and_leaves.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Jasminum fruticans</latin>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>shrub</tag>
        <family>Oleaceae</family>
        <abstract/>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Jasminum grandiflorum</latin>
        <common>Jasmine</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>climber</tag>
        <family>Oleaceae</family>
        <abstract>Jasminum grandiflorum, also known variously as the Spanish jasmine, Royal jasmine,
            Catalonian jasmine, among others (chameli in Urdu) is a species of jasmine native to
            South Asia, the Arabian peninsula (Oman, Saudi Arabia), Northeast Africa (Eritrea,
            Ethiopia, Djibouti, Somalia, Sudan), the African Great Lakes (Kenya, Uganda, Rwanda),
            and the Yunnan and Sichuan regions of China. The species is widely cultivated and is
            reportedly naturalized in République de Guinée, the Maldive Islands, Mauritius, Réunion,
            Java, the Cook Islands, Chiapas, Central America, and much of the West
            Indies.</abstract>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Jasminum odoratissimum</latin>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>shrub</tag>
        <family>Oleaceae</family>
        <abstract/>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Jasminum officinale</latin>
        <common>Jasmine</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>climber</tag>
        <family>Oleaceae</family>
        <abstract>Jasminum officinale, known as the common jasmine or simply jasmine, is a species
            of flowering plant in the olive family Oleaceae. It is native to the Caucasus, northern
            Iran, Afghanistan, Pakistan, the Himalayas, Tajikistan, India, Nepal and western China
            (Guizhou, Sichuan, Xizang (Tibet), Yunnan). The species is also widely cultivated in
            many places, and is reportedly naturalized in France, Italy, Portugal, Romania, the
            former Yugoslavia, Algeria, Florida and the West Indies. It is also known as summer
            jasmine, poet's jasmine, white jasmine, true jasmine or jessamine, and is particularly
            valued by gardeners throughout the temperate world for the intense fragrance of its
            flowers in summer. It is also the National flower of Pakistan.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Jasminum_officinale_-_Bot._Mag._31,_1787.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Juglans regia</latin>
        <common>Persian Walnut</common>
        <myphotos>walnut</myphotos>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Juglandaceae</family>
        <abstract>Juglans regia, Persian walnut, English walnut, or especially in Great Britain,
            common walnut, is an Old World walnut tree species native to the region stretching from
            the Balkans eastward to the Himalayas and southwest China. The largest forests are in
            Kyrgyzstan, where trees occur in extensive, nearly pure walnut forests at 1,000–2,000 m
            altitude—notably at Arslanbob in Jalal-Abad Province. It is widely cultivated across
            Europe.</abstract>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Juniperus oxycedrus</latin>
        <common>Prickly Juniper</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>shrub</tag>
        <family>Cupressaceae</family>
        <abstract>Juniperus oxycedrus (prickly juniper, prickly cedar, cade juniper and cade (from
            the French genévrier cade), sharp cedar) is a species of juniper, native across the
            Mediterranean region from Morocco and Portugal, north to southern France, east to
            westernmost Iran, and south to Lebanon and Israel, growing on a variety of rocky sites
            from sea level up to 1600 m altitude. The specific epithet oxycedrus means "sharp cedar"
            and this species may have been the original cedar or cedrus of the ancient
            Greeks.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Cade1.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Juniperus phoenicea</latin>
        <common>Phoenician Juniper</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>shrub</tag>
        <family>Cupressaceae</family>
        <abstract>Juniperus phoenicea, the Phoenicean juniper or Arâr, is a juniper found throughout
            the Mediterranean region, from Morocco and Portugal east to Italy, Turkey and Egypt,
            south on the mountains of Lebanon, Israel, Jordan, and in western Saudi Arabia near the
            Red Sea, and also on Madeira and the Canary Islands. It mostly grows at low altitudes
            close to the coast, but reaches 2,400 metres (7,900 ft) altitude in the south of its
            range in the Atlas Mountains. It is the vegetable symbol of the island of El
            Hierro.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Juniperus_phoenicea_berries.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Lagerstroemia indica</latin>
        <common>Cape Myrtle</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>shrub</tag>
        <family>Lythraceae</family>
        <abstract>Lagerstroemia indica (crape myrtle, crepe myrtle, crepeflower) is a species in the
            genus Lagerstroemia in the family Lythraceae. From China, Korea, Japan and Indian
            Subcontinent Lagerstroemia indica is an often multi-stemmed, deciduous tree with a wide
            spreading, flat topped, rounded, or even spike shaped open habit. Planted in full sun or
            under canopy, the tree is a popular nesting shrub for songbirds and wrens. The bark is a
            prominent feature being smooth, pinkish-gray and mottled, shedding each year. Leaves
            also shed each winter, after spectacular color display, and bare branches re-leaf early
            in the spring; leaves are small, smooth-edged, circular or oval-shaped, and dark green
            changing to yellow and orange and red in autumn. Flowers, on different trees, are white,
            pink, mauve, purple or carmine with crimped petals, in panicles up to 9 centimetres (3
            1⁄2 in). Lagerstroemia indica is frost tolerant, prefers full sun and will grow to 6
            metres (20 ft) with a spread of 6 metres (20 ft). Many hybrid cultivars have been
            developed between L. indica and L. faueri</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Lagerstroemia_indica_MHNT_Jardin_des_Plantes_de_Toulouse.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Lantana camara</latin>
        <common>Lantana</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>shrub</tag>
        <family>Verbenaceae</family>
        <abstract>Lantana camara, also known as big-sage (Malaysia), wild-sage, red-sage, white-sage
            (Caribbean) and tickberry (South Africa), is a species of flowering plant within the
            verbena family, Verbenaceae, that is native to the American tropics. Lantana camara,
            often planted to embellish gardens, has spread from its native Central and South America
            to around 50 different countries, where it has become an invasive species. It spread
            from the Americas into the rest of the world when it was brought back to Europe by Dutch
            explorers and cultivated widely, soon spreading into Asia and Oceania, where it
            established itself as a notorious weed. Lantana camara will often outcompete other more
            desirable species, leading to a reduction in biodiversity. It can also cause problems if
            it invades agricultural areas as a result of its toxicity to livestock as well as its
            ability to form dense thickets which if left unchecked can greatly reduce the
            productivity of farm land. The name Lantana derives from the Latin name of the wayfaring
            tree Viburnum lantana, the flowers of which closely resemble Lantana.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/LantanaFlowerLeaves.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Laurus nobilis</latin>
        <common>Bay tree</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Lauraceae</family>
        <abstract>Laurus nobilis is an aromatic evergreen tree or large shrub with green, glossy
            leaves, native to the Mediterranean region. It is one of the plants used for bay leaf
            seasoning in cooking. It is known as bay laurel, sweet bay, bay tree (esp. United
            Kingdom), true laurel, Grecian laurel, laurel tree or simply laurel. Laurus nobilis
            figures prominently in classical Greek, Roman, and Biblical culture. Worldwide, many
            other kinds of plants in diverse families are also called "bay" or "laurel", generally
            due to similarity of foliage or aroma to Laurus nobilis, and the full name is used for
            the California bay laurel (Umbellularia), also in the family Lauraceae.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Bay_leaf_pair443.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Ligustrum lucidum</latin>
        <common>Glossy Privet</common>
        <common>Chinese Privet</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>shrub</tag>
        <family>Oleeae</family>
        <abstract>Ligustrum lucidum (broad-leaf privet, Chinese privet glossy privet, tree privet or
            wax-leaf privet) is a species of privet (Ligustrum genus), a flowering plant in the
            olive family, Oleaceae, native to the southern half of China and naturalized in many
            places: Spain, Italy, Algeria, Canary Islands, New Zealand, Lesotho, South Africa,
            Japan, Korea, Australia, Norfolk Island, Chiapas, Central America, Argentina, and the
            southern United States (California, Arizona, Maryland, and the southeast from Texas to
            North Carolina). The name "Chinese privet" is more frequently used for Ligustrum
            sinense. The Latin lucidum means bright or shiny, and refers to the glossy
            leaves.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/FloweringLigustrumLucidumTree.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Livistona australis</latin>
        <common>Cabbage-tree palm</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>palm</tag>
        <family>Arecaceae</family>
        <abstract>The cabbage-tree palm, Livistona australis, is in the Arecaceae family. It is a
            tall, slender palm growing up to about 25 m in height and 0.35 m diameter. It is crowned
            with dark, glossy green leaves on petioles 2 m long. It has leaves plaited like a fan;
            the cabbage of these is small but sweet. In summer it bears flower spikes with sprigs of
            cream-white flowers. In winter, the trees accumulate dead fronds or leaves, which
            usually need to be removed by a arborist. Seeking protection from the sun, early
            European settlers in Australia used fibre from the native palm to create the cabbage
            tree hat, a distinctive form of headwear during the colonial era.</abstract>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Lonicera etrusca</latin>
        <common>Honeysuckle</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>climber</tag>
        <family>Caprifoliaceae</family>
        <abstract>Lonicera etrusca is a species of honeysuckle known by the common name Etruscan
            honeysuckle. It is native to Europe and it is known elsewhere, including the Pacific
            Northwest of North America, as an introduced species where it has escaped cultivation.
            It is kept in gardens as an ornamental plant. This is a deciduous perennial climber
            which can reach lengths of 6 meters. It is lined with oval leaves several centimeters
            long and bears dense spikes of flowers with pairs of fused leaves at the bases. Each
            flower has an elongated tubular corolla up to 5 centimeters long divided partway into
            two lips. The flower is light yellow to pale reddish-pink. The stamens and style
            protrude from the flower's mouth. The fruit is a bright red rounded berry. Notable
            cultivars include 'Donald Waterer' and 'Superba', which has gained the Royal
            Horticultural Society's Award of Garden Merit.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Lonicera_etrusca_1.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Magnolia grandiflora</latin>
        <common>Evergreen Magnolia</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Magnoliaceae</family>
        <abstract>Magnolia grandiflora, commonly known as the southern magnolia or bull bay, is a
            tree of the family Magnoliaceae native to the southeastern United States, from coastal
            North Carolina to central Florida, and west to East Texas and Oklahoma. Reaching 27.5 m
            (90 ft) in height, it is a large, striking evergreen tree with large, dark green leaves
            up to 20 cm (7.9 in) long and 12 cm (4.7 in) wide, and large, white, fragrant flowers up
            to 30 cm (12 in) in diameter. Although endemic to the lowland subtropical forests on the
            Gulf and south Atlantic coastal plain, magnolia grandiflora is widely cultivated in
            warmer areas around the world. The timber is hard and heavy, and has been used
            commercially to make furniture, pallets, and veneer.</abstract>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Melia azedarach</latin>
        <common>Indian Bead Tree</common>
        <common>Persian Lilac</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Meliaceae</family>
        <abstract>Melia azedarach, commonly known by many names, including chinaberry tree, Pride of
            India, bead-tree, Cape lilac, syringa berrytree, Persian lilac, and Indian lilac, is a
            species of deciduous tree in the mahogany family, Meliaceae, that is native to
            Indomalaya and Australasia.</abstract>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Morus alba</latin>
        <common>White Mulberry</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Moraceae</family>
        <abstract>Morus alba, known as white mulberry, is a short-lived, fast-growing, small to
            medium-sized mulberry tree, which grows to 10–20 m tall. The species is native to
            northern China, and is widely cultivated and naturalized elsewhere (United States,
            Mexico, Australia, Kyrgyzstan, Argentina, etc.). It is known as shahatut in Hindi शहतूत
            and Urdu شہتوت ,Tuta in Sanskrit, Tuti in Marathi, Dut in Turkish and Toot in Persian in
            Azerbaijani and in Armenian. The white mulberry is widely cultivated to feed the
            silkworms employed in the commercial production of silk. It is also notable for the
            rapid release of its pollen, which is launched at over half the speed of
            sound.</abstract>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Morus nigra</latin>
        <common>Black Mulberry</common>
        <vedel/>
        <myphotos>mulberry</myphotos>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Moraceae</family>
        <abstract>Morus nigra, called black mulberry or blackberry (not to be confused with the
            blackberries which are various species of Rubus), is a species of flowering plant in the
            family Moraceae, native to southwestern Asia, where it has been cultivated for so long
            that its precise natural range is unknown. It is known for its large number of
            chromosomes, as it has 154 pairs (308 individuals). Other mulberry species are sometimes
            confused with black mulberry, particularly black-fruited individuals of the white
            mulberry, but black mulberry can be distinguished by the uniformly hairy lower leaf
            surface.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Illustration_Morus_nigra0.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Myrtus communis</latin>
        <common>Myrtle</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>shrub</tag>
        <family>Myrtaceae</family>
        <abstract>Myrtus communis, the common myrtle, is an evergreen shrub native to southern
            Europe, north Africa, western Asia, Macaronesia, and the Indian Subcontinent, and also
            cultivated.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Myrtales_-_Myrtus_communis_1.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Nerium oleander</latin>
        <common>Oleander</common>
        <vedel/>
        <myphotos>oleander</myphotos>
        <tag>shrub</tag>
        <family>Apocynoideae</family>
        <abstract>Nerium oleander /ˈnɪəriəm ˈoʊliː.ændər/ is an evergreen shrub or small tree in the
            dogbane family Apocynaceae, toxic in all its parts. It is the only species currently
            classified in the genus Nerium. It is most commonly known as oleander, from its
            superficial resemblance to the unrelated olive Olea. It is so widely cultivated that no
            precise region of origin has been identified, though southwest Asia has been suggested.
            The ancient city of Volubilis in Morocco may have taken its name from the Berber name
            oualilt for the flower. Oleander is one of the most poisonous commonly grown garden
            plants.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Nerium_oleander_flowers_leaves.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Nicotiana glauca</latin>
        <common>Tree Tobacco</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>shrub</tag>
        <family>Solanaceae</family>
        <abstract>Nicotiana glauca is a species of wild tobacco known by the common name tree
            tobacco. Its leaves are attached to the stalk by petioles (many other Nicotiana species
            have sessile leaves), and its leaves and stems are neither pubescent nor sticky like
            Nicotiana tabacum. It resembles Cestrum parqui but differs in the form of leaves and
            fusion of the outer floral parts. It grows to heights of more than two meters. Tree
            tobacco is native to South America but it is now widespread as an introduced species on
            other continents. It is a common roadside weed in the southwestern United States, and an
            invasive plant species in California native plant habitats. The plant is used for a
            variety of medicinal purposes and smoked by Native American groups. The Cahuilla Indians
            used leaves interchangeably with other tobacco species in hunting rituals and as a
            poultice to treat swellings, bruises, cuts, wounds, boils, sores, inflamed throat, and
            swollen glands. Contains the toxic alkaloid anabasine. Ingestion of the leaves can be
            fatal. It is being investigated for use as a biofuel.</abstract>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Olea europaea</latin>
        <common>Olive Tree</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Oleaceae</family>
        <abstract>The olive, known by the botanical name Olea europaea, meaning "european olive", is
            a species of small tree in the family Oleaceae, found in the Mediterranean Basin from
            Portugal to the Levant, the Arabian Peninsula, and southern Asia as far east as China,
            as well as the Canary Islands, Mauritius and Réunion. The species is cultivated in many
            places and considered naturalized in all the countries of the Mediterranean coast, as
            well as in Argentina, Saudi Arabia, Java, Norfolk Island, California and Bermuda. Olea
            europeana sylvestris is a subspecies that corresponds to a smaller tree bearing
            noticeably smaller fruits. The olive's fruit, also called the olive, is of major
            agricultural importance in the Mediterranean region as the source of olive oil; it is
            one of the three core ingredients in Mediterranean cuisine. The tree and its fruit give
            their name to the plant family, which also includes species such as lilacs, jasmine,
            Forsythia and the true ash trees (Fraxinus). The word derives from Latin ŏlīva ("olive
            fruit", "olive tree"; "olive oil" is ŏlĕum) a borrowing from the Greek ἐλαία (elaía,
            "olive fruit", "olive tree") and ἔλαιον (élaion, "olive oil") in the archaic form
            *ἐλαίϝα. The oldest attested forms of the Greek words are the Mycenaean
            𐀁𐀨𐀷, e-ra-wa, and 𐀁𐀨𐀺, e-ra-wo or
            𐀁𐁉𐀺, e-rai-wo, written in the Linear B syllabic script. The word
            "oil" in multiple languages ultimately derives from the name of this tree and its
            fruit.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Olivesfromjordan.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Opuntia ficus-indica</latin>
        <common>Prickly Pear</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>shrub</tag>
        <family>Cactaceae</family>
        <abstract>Opuntia ficus-indica is a species of cactus that has long been a domesticated crop
            plant important in agricultural economies throughout arid and semiarid parts of the
            world. It is thought probably to have originated in Mexico. Some of the common English
            names for the plant and its fruit are Indian fig opuntia, Barbary fig, cactus pear,
            spineless cactus, and prickly pear, although this last name has also been applied to
            other less common Opuntia species. In Mexican Spanish, the plant is called nopal, while
            the fruit is called tuna, which are names also used in American English, especially as
            culinary terms.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Opuntia22_filtered.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Passiflora caerulea</latin>
        <common>Passion Flower</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>climber</tag>
        <family>Passifloraceae</family>
        <abstract>Passiflora caerulea, the blue passionflower, bluecrown passionflower or common
            passion flower, is a species of flowering plant native to South America (Argentina,
            Chile, Paraguay, Uruguay and Brazil). It is a vigorous, deciduous or semi-evergreen
            tendril vine growing to 10 m (33 ft) or more, with palmate leaves and fragrant,
            blue-white flowers with a prominent fringe of coronal filaments in bands of blue, white,
            and brown. The ovoid orange fruit, growing to 6 cm (2 in), is edible but
            bland.</abstract>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Paulownia tomentosa</latin>
        <common>Paulonia</common>
        <common>Foxglove Tree</common>
        <vedel/>
        <myphotos>paulonia</myphotos>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Paulowniaceae</family>
        <abstract>Paulownia tomentosa (common names princesstree, foxglove-tree, empress tree or
            kiri) is a deciduous tree in the family Paulowniaceae, native to central and western
            China. Paulownia tomentosa is an extremely fast-growing tree, and is a persistent exotic
            invasive in North America.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Paulownia_tomentosa_JPG2a.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Phaedranthus buccinatorius</latin>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>climber</tag>
        <family/>
        <abstract/>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Phillyrea angustifolia</latin>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>shrub</tag>
        <family>Oleeae</family>
        <abstract/>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Phillyrea latifolia</latin>
        <common>Green Olive Tree</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Oleeae</family>
        <abstract>Phillyrea latifolia, commonly known as green olive tree or mock privet, is a
            species of tree in the family Oleaceae.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Phillyrea_latifolia2.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Phoenix canariensis</latin>
        <common>Canary Date Palm</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>palm</tag>
        <family>Arecaceae</family>
        <abstract>Phoenix canariensis is a species of flowering plant in the palm family Arecaceae,
            native to the Canary Islands. It is a relative of Phoenix dactylifera, the true date
            palm. It is the natural symbol of the Canary Islands, together with the canary Serinus
            canaria.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Phoenix_canariensis,_Plaza_de_la_Catedral,_Almeria,_Spain.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Phoenix dactylifera</latin>
        <common>Date Palm</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>palm</tag>
        <family>Arecaceae</family>
        <abstract>Phoenix dactylifera, commonly known as date or date palm, is a flowering plant
            species in the palm family, Arecaceae, cultivated for its edible sweet fruit. Although
            its place of origin is unknown because of long cultivation, it probably originated from
            lands around Iraq. The species is widely cultivated and is naturalized in many tropical
            and subtropical regions worldwide. Date trees typically reach about 70–75 feet (21–23 m)
            in height, growing singly or forming a clump with several stems from a single root
            system. The leaves are 4–6 metres (13–20 ft) long, with spines on the petiole, and
            pinnate, with about 150 leaflets. The leaflets are 30 cm (12 in) long and 2 cm (0.79 in)
            wide. The full span of the crown ranges from 6–10 m (20–33 ft).</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Dates_on_date_palm.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Picea omorika</latin>
        <common>Serbian Spruce</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Pinaceae</family>
        <abstract>Picea omorika, common name Serbian spruce (Serbian: Панчићева оморика, Pančićeva
            omorika, pronounced [pâːnt͡ʃit͡ɕɛv̞a ɔmɔ̌rika]), is a species of coniferous tree endemic
            to the Drina River valley in eastern Bosnia and Herzegovina near Višegrad, and western
            Serbia, with a total range of only about 60 ha, at 800–1,600 m (2,625–5,249 ft)
            altitude. It was originally discovered near the village of Zaovine on the Tara Mountain
            in 1875, and named by the Serbian botanist Josif Pančić; the specific epithet omorika is
            simply the Serbian word for "Serbian spruce". All other spruces are smrča (смрча) in
            Serbian.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Picea_omorika1.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Picea orientalis</latin>
        <common>Oriental Spruce</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Pinaceae</family>
        <abstract>Picea orientalis, commonly known as the Oriental spruce or Caucasian spruce, is a
            species of spruce native to the Caucasus and adjacent northeast Turkey.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Doğu_ladini-1.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Pinus halepensis</latin>
        <common>Aleppo Pine</common>
        <vedel/>
        <myphotos>aleppo_pine</myphotos>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Pinaceae</family>
        <abstract>Pinus halepensis, commonly known as the Aleppo pine, is a pine native to the
            Mediterranean region. Its range extends from Morocco, Algeria and Spain north to
            southern France, Italy, Croatia, Montenegro, Albania, and east to Greece, all over Malta
            and northern Tunisia, with an outlying population (from which it was first described) in
            Syria, Lebanon, southern Turkey, Jordan, Israel, and Palestinian territories. In Israel
            it is called Jerusalem pine.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Calanques_--_Calanque_de_Port_Pin_-_Pinus_halepensis.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Pinus nigra</latin>
        <common>Black Pine</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Pinaceae</family>
        <abstract>Pinus nigra, the Austrian pine or black pine, is a moderately variable species of
            pine, occurring across southern Mediterranean Europe from Spain to the eastern
            Mediterranean on Anatolian peninsula of Turkey and on Corsica/Cyprus, including Crimea,
            and in the high mountains of the Maghreb in North Africa.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Forest_in_Bulgaria_near_Dundukovo_dam.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Pinus pinaster</latin>
        <common>Maritime Pine</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Pinaceae</family>
        <abstract>Pinus pinaster, the maritime pine or cluster pine, is a pine native to
            Mediterranean region.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Pinus_pinaster.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Pinus pinea</latin>
        <common>Stone Pine</common>
        <common>Umbrella Pine</common>
        <vedel/>
        <myphotos>umbrella_pine</myphotos>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Pinaceae</family>
        <abstract>The stone pine, with the botanical name Pinus pinea, is also called the Italian
            stone pine, umbrella pine and parasol pine. It is a tree from the pine family
            (Pinaceae). The tree is native to the Mediterranean region, occurring in Southern
            Europe, Israel, Lebanon and Syria. It is also naturalized in North Africa, the Canary
            Islands, South Africa and New South Wales. The species was introduced into North Africa
            millennia ago, such a long time that it is essentially indistinguishable from being
            native. Stone pines have been used and cultivated for their edible pine nuts since
            prehistoric times. They are widespread in horticultural cultivation as ornamental trees,
            planted in gardens and parks around the world. This plant has gained the Royal
            Horticultural Society's Award of Garden Merit.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Pinien_La_Brena2004.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Pistacia lentiscus</latin>
        <common>Mastic</common>
        <vedel/>
        <myphotos>mastic</myphotos>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <tag>dioecious</tag>
        <tag>evergreen</tag>
        <family>Anacardiaceae</family>
        <abstract>Pistacia lentiscus (also mastic; Greek: μαστίχα mastíkha ) is a dioecious
            evergreen shrub or small tree of the pistacio genus growing up to 4 m (13 ft) tall which
            is cultivated for its aromatic resin, mainly on the Greek island of Chios.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Pistacia_lentiscus.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Pistacia terebinthus</latin>
        <common>Turpentine Tree</common>
        <vedel/>
        <myphotos>turpentine</myphotos>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Anacardiaceae</family>
        <abstract>Pistacia terebinthus, known commonly as terebinth and turpentine tree, is a
            species of Pistacia, native to the Canary Islands, and the Mediterranean region from the
            western regions of Morocco, and Portugal to Greece, western and southeast Turkey. In the
            eastern shores of the Mediterranean sea – Syria, Lebanon and Israel – a similar species,
            Pistacia palaestina, fills the same ecological niche as this species and is also known
            as terebinth.</abstract>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Pistacia vera</latin>
        <common>Pistacio</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Anacardiaceae</family>
        <abstract>The pistachio (/pɪˈstɑːʃiˌoʊ, -ˈstæ-/, Pistacia vera), a member of the cashew
            family, is a small tree originating from Central Asia and the Middle East. The tree
            produces seeds that are widely consumed as food. Pistacia vera often is confused with
            other species in the genus Pistacia that are also known as pistachio. These other
            species can be distinguished by their geographic distributions (in the wild) and their
            seeds which are much smaller and have a soft shell.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Pistacchio_di_Bronte.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Pittosporum tobira</latin>
        <common>Australian Laurel</common>
        <vedel/>
        <myphotos>pittosporum</myphotos>
        <tag>shrub</tag>
        <family>Pittosporaceae</family>
        <abstract>Pittosporum tobira is a species of flowering plant in the Pittosporum family known
            by several common names, including Australian laurel, Japanese pittosporum, mock orange
            and Japanese cheesewood. It is native to Japan, China, and Korea, but it is used
            throughout the world as an ornamental plant in landscaping and as cut foliage. It is an
            evergreen shrub which can reach 10 m (33 ft) tall by 3 m (10 ft) broad, and can become
            treelike. It can also be trimmed into a hedge. The leaves are oval in shape with edges
            that curl under and measure up to 10 cm (4 in) in length. They are leathery, hairless,
            and darker and shinier on the upper surfaces. The inflorescence is a cluster of fragrant
            flowers occurring at the ends of branches. The flower has five white petals each about a
            centimetre long. The fruit is a hairy, woody capsule about 1 cm wide divided into three
            valves. Inside are black seeds in a bed of resinous pulp. The binomial qualifier tobira
            derives from the Japanese name for the plant. This shrub is a common, drought-tolerant
            and fairly hardy landscaping plant. Many cultivars have been developed, including dwarf
            forms and the popular 'Variegata', which has variegated leaves. It is used for hedges,
            living privacy screens, and indoor and outdoor planter boxes. The stems, leaves, and
            dried fruits are used in flower arrangements. The species and the cultivar 'Variegatum'
            have both gained the Royal Horticultural Society's Award of Garden Merit. Common pests
            of this plant include various aphids, mites, and leafhoppers, the cotton cushiony scale
            (Icerya purchasi), and root-knot nematodes (Meloidogyne spp.). It can be attacked by the
            pit-making pittosporum scale (Planchonia arabidis). It is vulnerable to the fungal plant
            pathogen Erythricium salmonicolor, which causes galls and the dieback disease known as
            pink limb blight.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Pittosporum_Tobira_JPG0.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Platanus orientalis</latin>
        <common>Oriental Plane</common>
        <vedel/>
        <myphotos>plane</myphotos>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Platanaceae</family>
        <abstract>Platanus orientalis, or oriental plane, is a large, deciduous tree of the
            Platanaceae family, growing to 30 m (98 ft) or more, and known for its longevity and
            spreading crown.</abstract>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Erythrina coralloides</latin>
        <common>Flame coral tree</common>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Fabaceae</family>
        <abstract>Erythrina coralloides (flame coral tree, naked coral tree) is a species of
            flowering tree in the pea family, Fabaceae, that is native to eastern Mexico. It ranges
            from Tamaulipas south to Oaxaca, and some taxonomists believe it is also native to
            southern Arizona in the United States.</abstract>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Platanus x acerifolia</latin>
        <common>London Plane</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Platanaceae</family>
        <abstract/>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Plumbago capensis</latin>
        <common>Plumbago</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>climber</tag>
        <family>Plumbaginaceae</family>
        <abstract>Plumbago auriculata (common names blue plumbago, Cape plumbago or Cape leadwort),
            syn. P. capensis, is a species of flowering plant in the family Plumbaginaceae, native
            to South Africa. It is an evergreen shrub, often grown as a climber, ascending rapidly
            to 6 m (20 ft) tall by 3 m (10 ft) wide in nature, though much smaller when cultivated
            as a houseplant. It has light blue to blue flowers and also variations with white (P.
            auriculata var. alba) or deep blue (P. auriculata 'Royal cape') flowers. The leaves are
            a glossy green and grow to 5 cm (2 in) long. Plumbago grow best in full sun to part
            shade. The specific epithet auriculata means "with ears", referring to the shape of the
            leaves. In temperate regions it may be grown outside in frost free areas, otherwise
            under glass. The species and the white-flowered form P. auriculata f. alba have both
            gained the Royal Horticultural Society's Award of Garden Merit. Plumbago auriculata is a
            medicinal herb plant, the name has a root from the Latin word plumbum, meaning lead,
            because it has some pharmaceutical effects for lead poisoning (Asha Saji, V. T.
            Antony,2015) . Also its used as a phytoremediator for lead and cadmium. Medicinal uses
            and phytochemistry: This plant usually used in traditional medicine in India, like
            treating wounds, broken bones, and headache. Many secondary metabolites have been
            discovered and isolated from Plumbago auriculata such as Plumbagin, palmitic acids.
            Propagation: Plumbago auriculata could be propagated sexually by seeds and asexual by
            cutting in summer. Its need well aerated soil and light. it is also preferring the
            acidic soil. watering: Plumbago auriculata, have to stages for watering, the first at
            the beginning of growth, the soil should be always watered, once the plant is standing
            well, it should be watered in needs only. Nutrition: Plumbago auriculata ma suffer from
            lacking some nutrients, so it should be fertilized with the appropriate
            nutrients.</abstract>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Paliurus spina-christi</latin>
        <common>Christ's Thorns</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>shrub</tag>
        <family>Rhamnaceae</family>
        <abstract>Paliurus spina-christi, commonly known as Jerusalem thorn, garland thorn, Christ's
            thorn, or crown of thorns, is a species of Paliurus native to the Mediterranean region
            and southwest and central Asia, from Morocco and Spain east to Iran and Tajikistan. It
            is a deciduous shrub or small tree growing to 3–4 m tall. The shoots are zig-zagged,
            with a leaf and two stipular spines (one straight, one curved) on the outside of each
            kink. The leaves are oval, 2–5 cm long and 1–4 cm broad, glossy green, with an entire
            margin. The fruit is a dry woody nutlet centred in a circular wing 2–3.5 cm diameter.
            The name reflects an old legend that the spiny branches were used to make the crown of
            thorns placed on Christ's head before his crucifixion. It is viewed as an ornamental
            curiosity and is cultivated in some areas spreading its range, including Fiji. The
            Christ's Thorn Jujube, is also identified as being used for the thorn crown.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Paliurus_fg01.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Populus nigra 'Italica'</latin>
        <common>Lombardy Poplar</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family/>
        <abstract/>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Prunus armeniaca</latin>
        <common>Apricot</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Rosaceae</family>
        <abstract>Prunus armeniaca ("Armenian plum"), the most commonly cultivated apricot species,
            also called ansu apricot, Siberian apricot, Tibetan apricot, is a species of Prunus,
            classified with the plum in the subgenus Prunus. The native range is somewhat uncertain
            due to its extensive prehistoric cultivation, though almost certainly somewhere in Asia.
            It is extensively cultivated in many countries and has escaped into the wild in many
            places.</abstract>
        <picture>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Apricots.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Prunus dulcis</latin>
        <latin>Prunus amygdalus</latin>
        <common>Almond</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Rosaceae</family>
        <abstract>(For other uses, see Almond (disambiguation).)("Badam" redirects here. For some
            villages in Iran, see Badam (disambiguation).) The almond (Prunus dulcis, syn. Prunus
            amygdalus) is a species of tree native to the Middle East, the Indian Subcontinent and
            North Africa. "Almond" is also the name of the edible and widely cultivated seed of this
            tree. Within the genus Prunus, it is classified with the peach in the subgenus
            Amygdalus, distinguished from the other subgenera by the corrugated shell (endocarp)
            surrounding the seed. The fruit of the almond is a drupe, consisting of an outer hull
            and a hard shell with the seed, which is not a true nut, inside. Shelling almonds refers
            to removing the shell to reveal the seed. Almonds are sold shelled or unshelled.
            Blanched almonds are shelled almonds that have been treated with hot water to soften the
            seedcoat, which is then removed to reveal the white embryo.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Prunus_dulcis_-_Köhler–s_Medizinal-Pflanzen-250.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Prunus lusitanica</latin>
        <common>Portugal Laurel</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>shrub</tag>
        <family>Rosaceae</family>
        <abstract>Prunus lusitanica, the Portugal laurel, is a species of the genus Prunus, related
            to the cherry. It is native to southwestern France, Spain, Portugal, Morocco, and
            Macaronesia (the Azores, Canary Islands and Madeira).</abstract>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Prunus persica</latin>
        <common>Peach</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Rosaceae</family>
        <abstract>The peach (Prunus persica) is a deciduous tree native to the region of Northwest
            China between the Tarim Basin and the north slopes of the Kunlun Shan mountains, where
            it was first domesticated and cultivated. It bears an edible juicy fruit called a peach
            or a nectarine. The specific epithet persica refers to its widespread cultivation in
            Persia, whence it was transplanted to Europe. It belongs to the genus Prunus which
            includes the cherry, apricot, almond and plum, in the rose family. The peach is
            classified with the almond in the subgenus Amygdalus, distinguished from the other
            subgenera by the corrugated seed shell. Peach and nectarines are the same species, even
            though they are regarded commercially as different fruits. In contrast to peaches, whose
            fruits present the characteristic fuzz on the skin, nectarines are characterized by the
            absence of fruit-skin trichomes (fuzz-less fruit); genetic studies suggest nectarines
            are produced due to a recessive allele, whereas peaches are produced from a dominant
            allele for fuzzy skin. The People's Republic of China is the world's largest producer of
            peaches.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Illustration_Prunus_persica0.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Punica granatum</latin>
        <common>Pomegranate</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>shrub</tag>
        <family>Lythraceae</family>
        <abstract>The pomegranate (/ˈpɒmᵻɡrænᵻt/), botanical name Punica granatum, is a
            fruit-bearing deciduous shrub or small tree in the family Lythraceae that grows between
            5 and 8 m (16 and 26 ft) tall. In the Northern Hemisphere, the fruit is typically in
            season from September to February, and in the Southern Hemisphere from March to May. As
            intact arils or juice, pomegranates are used in cooking, baking, meal garnishes, juice
            blends, smoothies, and alcoholic beverages, such as cocktails and wine. The pomegranate
            originated in the region of modern-day Iran and has been cultivated since ancient times
            throughout the Mediterranean region and northern India. It was introduced into Spanish
            America in the late 16th century and California by Spanish settlers in 1769. Today, it
            is widely cultivated throughout the Middle East and Caucasus region, north Africa and
            tropical Africa, the Indian subcontinent, Central Asia, the drier parts of southeast
            Asia, and parts of the Mediterranean Basin. It is also cultivated in parts of California
            and Arizona. In recent years, it has become more common in the commercial markets of
            Europe and the Western Hemisphere.</abstract>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Pyrostegia venusta</latin>
        <common>Orange trumpetvine</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>climber</tag>
        <family>Bignoniaceae</family>
        <abstract>Pyrostegia venusta, also commonly known as flamevine or orange trumpetvine, is a
            plant species of the genus Pyrostegia of the family Bignoniaceae originally endemic to
            Brazil, but nowadays a well-known garden species.</abstract>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Quercus cerris</latin>
        <common>Turkey Oak</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Fagaceae</family>
        <abstract>Quercus cerris, the Turkey oak or Austrian oak, is an oak native to south-eastern
            Europe and Asia Minor. It is the type species of Quercus sect. Cerris, a section of the
            genus characterised by shoot buds surrounded by soft bristles, bristle-tipped leaf
            lobes, and acorns that usually mature in 18 months.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Quercus_cerris_folliage.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Quercus coccifera</latin>
        <common>Kermes Oak</common>
        <vedel/>
        <myphotos>kermes</myphotos>
        <tag>shrub</tag>
        <family>Fagaceae</family>
        <abstract>Quercus coccifera, the kermes oak, is an oak in the Quercus section Cerris. It is
            native to the Mediterranean region and Northern African Maghreb, south to north from
            Morocco to France and west to east from Portugal to Cyprus and Turkey, crossing Spain,
            Italy, Libya, Balkans, and Greece, including Crete. The Kermes Oak was historically
            important as the food plant of the Kermes scale insect, from which a red dye called
            crimson was obtained. The etymology of the specific name 'coccifera' is related to the
            production of red cochineal (crimson) dye and derived from Latin coccum which was from
            Greek κὀκκος, the kermes insect. The Latin -fera means 'bearer'.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Quercus_coccifera.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Quercus ilex</latin>
        <common>Holm Oak</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Fagaceae</family>
        <abstract>Quercus ilex, the evergreen oak, holly oak or holm oak, is a large evergreen oak
            native to the Mediterranean region. It takes its name from holm, an ancient name for
            holly. It is a member of the white oak section of the genus, with acorns that mature in
            a single summer. The first trees to be planted from acorns into England are still to be
            found growing within the stately grounds of Mamhead Park, Devon. Britton &amp; Brayley
            said of Mamhead's grounds The Beauties of England and Wales (1803): The TROBI Champion
            in Gloucestershire measured 27 1⁄4 ft (8.3 m) in circumference at 1.2 m height in 1993.
            A specimen in Milo, in Sicily, is reputed to be 700 years old while a small population
            on the slopes of northern village of Wardija in Malta are said to be between 500 and
            1,000 years old. Prior to the Carthaginian period, holm oak was prevalent on the
            islands.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Quercus_ilex_rotundifolia.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Quercus macrolepis</latin>
        <common>Valonia oak</common>
        <myphotos>valonia</myphotos>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Fagaceae</family>
        <abstract>Quercus macrolepis, the Valonia oak, is a tree in the family Fagaceae. It used to
            be considered a subspecies of Quercus ithaburensis or a hybrid of Quercus libani. It
            appears to be closely related to Quercus brantii but with cupscales less curved and the
            cup covering almost all the fruit with sunken apex and shorter petiole.</abstract>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Quercus suber</latin>
        <common>Cork Oak</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Fagaceae</family>
        <abstract>Quercus suber, commonly called the cork oak, is a medium-sized, evergreen oak tree
            in the section Quercus sect. Cerris. It is the primary source of cork for wine bottle
            stoppers and other uses, such as cork flooring. It is native to southwest Europe and
            northwest Africa. It grows to up to 20 m (66 ft), although it is typically more stunted
            in its native environment. The leaves are 4 to 7 cm (1.6 to 2.8 in) long, weakly lobed
            or coarsely toothed, dark green above, paler beneath, with the leaf margins often
            downcurved. The acorns are 2 to 3 cm (0.79 to 1.18 in) long, in a deep cup fringed with
            elongated scales.</abstract>
        <picture>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Cork_tree.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Rhamnus alaternus</latin>
        <common>Mediterranean Blackthorn</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>shrub</tag>
        <family>Rhamnaceae</family>
        <abstract>Rhamnus alaternus is a species of flowering plant in the buckthorn family known by
            the common name of Italian buckthorn or Mediterranean buckthorn.</abstract>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Ricinus communis</latin>
        <common>Castor Oil Plant</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>shrub</tag>
        <family>Euphorbiaceae</family>
        <abstract>Ricinus communis, the castorbean or castor-oil-plant, is a species of flowering
            plant in the spurge family, Euphorbiaceae. It is the sole species in the monotypic
            genus, Ricinus, and subtribe, Ricininae. The evolution of castor and its relation to
            other species are currently being studied using modern genetic tools. It reproduces with
            a mixed pollination system which favor selfing by geitonogamy but at the same time can
            be an out-crosser by anemophily or entomophily. Its seed is the castor bean, which,
            despite its name, is not a true bean. Castor is indigenous to the southeastern
            Mediterranean Basin, Eastern Africa, and India, but is widespread throughout tropical
            regions (and widely grown elsewhere as an ornamental plant). Castor seed is the source
            of castor oil, which has a wide variety of uses. The seeds contain between 40% and 60%
            oil that is rich in triglycerides, mainly ricinolein. The seed also contains ricin, a
            water-soluble toxin, which is also present in lower concentrations throughout the plant.
            An unrelated plant species, Fatsia japonica, is similar in appearance and known as the
            false castor oil plant.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Ricinus_March_2010-1.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Rosmarinus officinalis</latin>
        <common>Rosemary</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>shrub</tag>
        <family>Lamiaceae</family>
        <abstract>Rosmarinus officinalis, commonly known as rosemary, is a woody, perennial herb
            with fragrant, evergreen, needle-like leaves and white, pink, purple, or blue flowers,
            native to the Mediterranean region. It is a member of the mint family Lamiaceae, which
            includes many other herbs. The name "rosemary" derives from the Latin for "dew" (ros)
            and "sea" (marinus), or "dew of the sea". The plant is also sometimes called anthos,
            from the ancient Greek word ἄνθος, meaning "flower". Rosemary has a fibrous root
            system.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Rosemary_bush.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Roystonea regia</latin>
        <common>Royal Palm</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>palm</tag>
        <family>Arecaceae</family>
        <abstract>Roystonea regia, commonly known as the Cuban royal palm, Florida royal palm, or
            simply the royal palm is a species of palm which is native to southern Florida, Mexico
            and parts of Central America and the Caribbean. A large and attractive palm, it has been
            planted throughout the tropics and subtropics as an ornamental tree. Although it is
            sometimes called R. elata, the conserved name R. regia is now the correct name for the
            species. Populations in Cuba and Florida were long seen as separate species, but are now
            considered to belong to a single species. Best known as an ornamental, R. regia is also
            used as a source of thatch, construction timber, and in some forms of so-called
            traditional medicine, although there is currently no valid scientific evidence to
            support the efficacy or use of any palm species for medicinal purposes. The fruit is
            eaten by birds and bats (which disperse the seeds) and fed to livestock. Its flowers are
            visited by birds and bats, and it serves as a roosting site and food source for a
            variety of animals. Roystonea regia is the national tree of Cuba, and has a religious
            role both in Santería and Christianity, where it is used in Palm Sunday
            observances.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Roystonea_regia.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Styphnolobium japonicum</latin>
        <common>Pagoda Tree</common>
        <common>Scholar's Tree</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Fabaceae</family>
        <abstract>Styphnolobium japonicum (L.) Schott, the Japanese pagoda tree (Chinese scholar
            tree, pagoda tree; syn. Sophora japonica) is a species of tree in the subfamily
            Faboideae of the pea family Fabaceae. It was formerly included within a broader
            interpretation of the genus Sophora. The species of Styphnolobium differ from Sophora in
            lacking the ability to form symbioses with rhizobia (nitrogen fixing bacteria) on their
            roots. It also differs from the related genus Calia (mescalbeans) in having deciduous
            leaves and flowers in axillary, not terminal, racemes. The leaves are alternate,
            pinnate, with 9-21 leaflets, and the flowers in pendulous racemes similar to those of
            the Black locust.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Sophora_japonica_JPG2Aa.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Schinus molle</latin>
        <common>Peruvian pepper</common>
        <common>Peruvian Mastic Tree</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Anacardiaceae</family>
        <abstract>Schinus molle (Peruvian pepper , also known as American pepper, Peruvian
            peppertree, escobilla, false pepper, molle del Peru, pepper tree, peppercorn tree,
            Californian pepper tree, pirul and Peruvian mastic) is an evergreen tree that grows to
            15 meters (50 feet). It is native to the Peruvian Andes. The bright pink fruits of
            Schinus molle are often sold as "pink peppercorns" although S. molle is unrelated to
            true pepper (Piper nigrum). The tree is host to Bombycomorpha bifascia, known as the
            Pepper-tree moth.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Schinus_Molle.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Schinus terebinthifolia</latin>
        <common>Brazilian peppertree</common>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <tag>Almeria</tag>
        <family>Anacardiaceae</family>
        <abstract>Schinus terebinthifolia is a species of flowering plant in the cashew family,
            Anacardiaceae, that is native to subtropical and tropical South America (southeastern
            Brazil, northern Argentina, and Paraguay). It is found in these states of Brazil:
            Alagoas, Bahia, Espírito Santo, Mato Grosso do Sul, Minas Gerais, Pernambuco, Paraná,
            Rio de Janeiro, Rio Grande do Norte, Rio Grande do Sul, Santa Catarina, São Paulo, and
            Sergipe. Common names include Brazilian peppertree, aroeira, rose pepper, broadleaved
            pepper tree, wilelaiki (or wililaiki), Christmasberry, and Florida Holly.</abstract>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Spartium junceum</latin>
        <common>Spanish Broom</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>shrub</tag>
        <family>Genisteae</family>
        <abstract>Spartium junceum, commonly known as Spanish broom or weaver's broom, is a species
            of flowering plant in the family Fabaceae, native to the Mediterranean in southern
            Europe, southwest Asia and northwest Africa, where it is found in sunny sites, usually
            on dry, sandy soils. It is the sole species in the genus Spartium, but is closely
            related to the other brooms in the genera Cytisus and Genista. There are many binomials
            in Spartium that are of dubious validity (see below). The Latin specific epithet junceum
            means "rush-like", referring to the shoots, which show a passing resemblance to those of
            the rush genus Juncus.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Spartium_junceum_(habitus).jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Tamarix aphylla</latin>
        <common>Tamerisk</common>
        <vedel/>
        <myphotos>tamerisk</myphotos>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Tamaricaceae</family>
        <abstract>Tamarix aphylla is the largest known species of Tamarix (height: to 18 metres–60
            ft). The species has a variety of common names, including Athel tamarisk, Athel tree,
            Athel pine, and saltcedar. It is an evergreen tree, native across North, East and
            Central Africa, through the Middle East, and into parts of Western and Southern
            Asia.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Tamaris3.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Tamarix gallica</latin>
        <common>Tamerisk</common>
        <vedel/>
        <myphotos>tamerisk</myphotos>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Tamaricaceae</family>
        <abstract>amarix gallica, the French tamarisk, is a deciduous, herbaceous, twiggy shrub or
            small tree reaching up to about 5 meters high. It is indigenous to Saudi Arabia and the
            Sinai Peninsula, and very common around the Mediterranean region. It is present in many
            other areas as an invasive introduced species, often becoming a noxious weed. It was
            first described for botanical classification by the taxonomist Carl Linnaeus in 1753,
            but had already been in cultivation since 1596.</abstract>
        <picture/>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Tecomaria capensis</latin>
        <common>Cape Honeysuckle</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>climber</tag>
        <family>Bignoniaceae</family>
        <abstract>Tecoma capensis (common name Cape honeysuckle) is a species of flowering plant in
            the family Bignoniaceae, native to southern Africa. Despite its common name, it is not
            closely related to the true honeysuckle.</abstract>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Platycladus orientalis</latin>
        <latin>Thuja orientalis</latin>
        <common>Chinese Thuja</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <family>Cupressaceae</family>
        <abstract>Platycladus is a distinct genus of evergreen coniferous tree in the cypress family
            Cupressaceae, containing only one species, Platycladus orientalis, also known as Chinese
            thuja, Oriental arborvitae, Chinese arborvitae, biota or oriental thuja. It is native to
            northwestern China, Korea, and the Russian Far East (Amur + Khabarovsk). It is also now
            naturalised as an introduced species elsewhere in Asia: eastward to Japan; southward to
            northern India; and westward to northern Iran.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Platycladus_orientalis.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Viburnum tinus</latin>
        <common>Laurrestinus</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>shrub</tag>
        <family>Adoxaceae</family>
        <abstract>Viburnum tinus (Laurustinus, laurustinus viburnum, or laurestine) is a species of
            flowering plant in the family Adoxaceae, native to the Mediterranean area of Europe and
            North Africa. Laurus signifies the leaves' similarities to bay laurel.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Viburnum_tinus00.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Vinca major</latin>
        <common>Greater Periwinkle</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>climber</tag>
        <family>Apocynaceae</family>
        <abstract>Vinca major, with the common names bigleaf periwinkle, large periwinkle, greater
            periwinkle and blue periwinkle, is species of flowering plant in the family Apocynaceae,
            native to the western Mediterranean. Growing to 25 cm (10 in) tall and spreading
            indefinitely, it is an evergreen perennial, frequently used in cultivation as
            groundcover.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Vinca_major_NS.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Vitex agnus-castus</latin>
        <common>Chaste Tree</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>shrub</tag>
        <family>Verbenaceae</family>
        <abstract>Vitex agnus-castus, also called vitex, chaste tree, chasteberry, Abraham's balm,
            lilac chastetree, or monk's pepper, is a native of the Mediterranean region. It is one
            of the few temperate-zone species of Vitex, which is on the whole a genus of tropical
            and sub-tropical flowering plants. Theophrastus mentioned the shrub several times, as
            agnos (άγνος) in Enquiry into Plants. It has been long believed to be an anaphrodisiac
            but its effectiveness remains controversial.</abstract>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Vitis vinifera</latin>
        <common>Grape Vine</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>shrub</tag>
        <family>Vitaceae</family>
        <abstract>Vitis vinifera (common grape vine) is a species of Vitis, native to the
            Mediterranean region, central Europe, and southwestern Asia, from Morocco and Portugal
            north to southern Germany and east to northern Iran. There are currently between 5,000
            and 10,000 varieties of Vitis vinifera grapes though only a few are of commercial
            significance for wine and table grape production. It is a liana growing to 35 yards (32
            m) in length, with flaky bark. The leaves are alternate, palmately lobed, 5–20 cm
            (2.0–7.9 in) long and broad. The fruit is a berry, known as a grape; in the wild species
            it is 6 mm (0.24 in) diameter and ripens dark purple to blackish with a pale wax bloom;
            in cultivated plants it is usually much larger, up to 3 cm (1.2 in) long, and can be
            green, red, or purple (black). The species typically occurs in humid forests and
            streamsides. The wild grape is often classified as V. vinifera subsp. sylvestris (in
            some classifications considered Vitis sylvestris), with V. vinifera subsp. vinifera
            restricted to cultivated forms. Domesticated vines have hermaphrodite flowers, but
            subsp. sylvestris is dioecious (male and female flowers on separate plants) and
            pollination is required for fruit to develop. The grape is eaten fresh, processed to
            make wine or juice, or dried to produce raisins. Cultivars of Vitis vinifera form the
            basis of the majority of wines produced around the world. All of the familiar wine
            varieties belong to Vitis vinifera, which is cultivated on every continent except for
            Antarctica, and in all the major wine regions of the world.</abstract>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Washingtonia filifera</latin>
        <common>Fan-leaved Palm</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>palm</tag>
        <family>Arecaceae</family>
        <abstract>Washingtonia filifera, also known as desert fan palm or California fan palm or
            California palm, is a flowering plant in the palm family (Arecaceae), and native to the
            southwestern U.S. and Baja California. Growing to 15–20 m (49–66 ft) tall by 3–6 m
            (10–20 ft) broad, it is an evergreen monocot with a tree-like growth habit. It has a
            sturdy columnar trunk and waxy fan-shaped (palmate) leaves.</abstract>
        <picture>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/Washingtonia_filifera.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Ziziphus jujube</latin>
        <common>Common Jujube</common>
        <vedel/>
        <tag>shrub</tag>
        <family>Rhamnaceae</family>
        <abstract>Ziziphus jujuba (from Greek ζίζυφον, zízyphon), commonly called jujube
            (/ˈdʒuːdʒuːb/; sometimes jujuba), red date, Chinese date, Korean date, or Indian date is
            a species of Ziziphus in the buckthorn family (Rhamnaceae). It is used primarily as a
            shade tree that also bears fruit.</abstract>
        <picture>http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/Special:FilePath/ZiziphusJujubaVarSpinosa.jpg</picture>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Juniperus communis</latin>
        <common>Common Juniper</common>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <pandh/>
        <family>Cupressaceae</family>
        <abstract>Juniperus communis, the common juniper, is a species of conifer in the genus
            Juniperus, in the family Cupressaceae. It has the largest geographical range of any
            woody plant, with a circumpolar distribution throughout the cool temperate Northern
            Hemisphere from the Arctic south in mountains to around 30°N latitude in North America,
            Europe and Asia. Relict populations can be found in the Atlas Mountains of
            Africa.</abstract>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Robinia pseudoacacia</latin>
        <common>Robinia</common>
        <common>False Acacia</common>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <pandh/>
        <family>Fabaceae</family>
        <abstract>Robinia pseudoacacia, commonly known in its native territory as black locust, is a
            medium-sized deciduous tree native to the southeastern United States, but it has been
            widely planted and naturalized elsewhere in temperate North America, Europe, Southern
            Africa and Asia and is considered an invasive species in some areas. Another common name
            is false acacia, a literal translation of the specific name It was introduced into
            Britain in 1636.</abstract>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Pulmeria rubra</latin>
        <common>Frangipani</common>
        <tag>shrub</tag>
        <family>Apocynaceae</family>
        <abstract>Plumeria rubra is a deciduous plant species belonging to the genus Plumeria.[3]
            Originally native to Mexico, Central America, Colombia and Venezuela, it has been widely
            cultivated in subtropical and tropical climates worldwide and is a popular garden and
            park plant, as well as being used in temples and cemeteries. It grows as a spreading
            tree to 7–8 m (23–26 ft) high and wide, and is flushed with fragrant flowers of shades
            of pink, white and yellow over the summer and autumn. Its common names include
            frangipani, red paucipan, red-jasmine, red frangipani, common frangipani,
            temple tree, or simply plumeria.</abstract>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Calicotome spinosa</latin>
        <common>Thorny Broom</common>
        <family>Fabaceae</family>
        <tag>shrub</tag>
        <pandh/>
        <abstract>Calicotome spinosa (known as thorny broom or spiny broom) is a very spiny, densely
            branched shrub of the legume family Fabaceae which can reach up to three metres in
            height. It grows in the Western Mediterranean region on sunny slopes and dry, rocky
            ground. It is found in Spain, France, Italy, Croatia and Algeria and has been introduced
            to New Zealand. From March to June it produces bright yellow flowers which are borne
            singly or in small clusters. The seed-pods are 30mm long and are almost hairless, unlike
            those of the similar species Calicotome villosa.</abstract>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Liquidambar orientalis</latin>
        <common>Turkish sweetgum</common>
        <family>Altingiaceae</family>
        <tag>tree</tag>
        <abstract>Liquidambar orientalis, commonly known as oriental sweetgum or Turkish sweetgum,
            is a deciduous tree in the genus Liquidambar, native to the eastern Mediterranean
            region, that occurs as pure stands mainly in the floodplains of southwestern Turkey and
            on the Greek island of Rhodes.</abstract>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Bauhinia variegata</latin>
        <family>Fabaceae</family>
        <common>Orchid tree</common>
        <tag>Antalya</tag>
        <abstract>Bauhinia variegata is a species of flowering plant in the family Fabaceae. It is
            native to South Asia and Southeast Asia, from southern China, Burma, India, Nepal,
            Pakistan, and Sri Lanka. Common names include orchid tree, camel's foot tree, kachnar
            and mountain-ebony.<br/> It is a small to medium-sized tree growing to 10–12 metres
            (33–39 ft) tall, deciduous in the dry season. The leaves are 10–20 centimetres (3.9–7.9
            in) obcordate shaped, long and broad, rounded, and bilobed at the base and apex. The
            flowers are conspicuous, bright pink or white, 8–12 centimetres (3.1–4.7 in) diameter,
            with five petals. The fruit is a pod 15–30 centimetres (5.9–11.8 in) long, containing
            several seeds.</abstract>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Leucaena leucocephala</latin>
        <family>Fabaceae</family>
        <tag>Antalya</tag>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Eucalyptus camaldulensis</latin>
        <family>Myrtaceae</family>
        <tag>Antalya</tag>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Ficus retusa</latin>
        <family>Moraceae</family>
        <tag>Antalya</tag>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Washingtonia robusta</latin>
        <family>Arecaceae</family>
        <tag>Antalya</tag>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Syagrus romanzoffiana</latin>
        <family>Arecaceae</family>
        <tag>Antalya</tag>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Pinus brutia</latin>
        <family>Pinaceae</family>
        <tag>Antalya</tag>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Grevillea robusta</latin>
        <family>Proteceae</family>
        <common>Silky Oak</common>
        <tag>Antalya</tag>
        <tag>Bodrum</tag>
        <abstract>Grevillea robusta, commonly known as the southern silky oak, silk oak or silky
            oak, silver oak or Australian silver oak, is a flowering plant in the family Proteaceae.
            It is a tree, the largest species in its genus but is not closely related to the true
            oaks, Quercus. It is a native of eastern coastal Australia, growing in riverine,
            subtropical and dry rainforest environments.</abstract>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Ceiba speciosa</latin>
        <latin>Chorisia speciosa</latin>
        <common>Silk floss tree</common>
        <family>Bombacaceae</family>
        <tag>Antalya</tag>
        <tag>Mgaar</tag>
        <abstract>The silk floss tree (Ceiba speciosa, formerly Chorisia speciosa), is a species of
            deciduous tree native to the tropical and subtropical forests of South America. It has a
            host of local common names, such as palo borracho (in Spanish literally "drunken
            stick"), samu'ũ (in Guarani) or paineira (in Brazilian Portuguese). In Bolivia it is
            called Toborochi, means "tree of refuge" or "sheltering tree".] It belongs to the same
            family as the baobab and the kapok. Another tree of the same genus, Ceiba chodatii, is
            often referred to by the same common names.</abstract>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Cupressus arizonica</latin>
        <family>Cupressaceae</family>
        <tag>Antalya</tag>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Ligustrum japonicum</latin>
        <family>Oleaceae</family>
        <tag>Antalya</tag>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Prunus nigra</latin>
        <family>Rosaceae</family>
        <tag>Antalya</tag>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Cascabela thevetia</latin>
        <latin>Thevetia peruvina</latin>
        <latin>Cascabela peruviana</latin>
        <common>Yellow Oleander</common>
        <family>Apocynacea</family>
        <tag>shrub</tag>
        <abstract>Cascabela thevetia is a poisonous plant native throughout Mexico and in Central America, and cultivated widely as an ornamental. It is a relative of Nerium oleander, giving it a common name yellow oleander, and is also called lucky nut in the West Indies.
       </abstract>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Taxus baccata</latin>
        <family>Taxaceae</family>
        <tag>Antalya</tag>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Malus floribundo</latin>
        <family>Rosaceae</family>
        <tag>Antalya</tag>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Prunus cerasifera-nigra</latin>
        <family>Rosaceae</family>
        <tag>Antalya</tag>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Persea americana</latin>
        <common>Avocado</common>
        <family>Lauraceae</family>
        <tag>Estapone</tag>
        <abstract>The avocado is a tree, long thought to have originated in South Central Mexico, classified as a member of the flowering plant family Lauraceae. The fruit of the plant, also called an avocado (or avocado pear or alligator pear), is botanically a large berry containing a single large seed known as a "pit" or a "stone".</abstract>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Brachychiton acerifolius</latin>
        <common>Illawarra flame tree</common>
        <family>Malvaceae</family>
        <tag>Ponta Delgada</tag>
        <abstract>Brachychiton acerifoliusis a large tree of the family Malvaceae[a] native to subtropical regions on the east coast of Australia. It is famous for the bright red bell-shaped flowers that often cover the whole tree when it is leafless. Along with other members of the genus Brachychiton, it is commonly referred to as a Kurrajong.</abstract>
    </species>
    <species>
        <latin>Metrosideros excelsa</latin>
        <common>Pohutukawa</common>
        <family>Myrtaceae</family>
        <tag>Azores</tag>
        <abstract>Metrosideros excelsa, with common names pōhutukawa, New Zealand pohutukawa, New Zealand Christmas tree, New Zealand Christmas bush, and iron tree, is a coastal evergreen tree in the myrtle family, Myrtaceae, that produces a brilliant display of red (or occasionally orange, yellow or white) flowers made up of a mass of stamens. The pōhutukawa is one of twelve Metrosideros species endemic to New Zealand. Renowned for its vibrant colour and its ability to survive even perched on rocky, precarious cliffs, it has found an important place in New Zealand culture for its strength and beauty and is regarded as a chiefly tree (rākau rangatira) by Māori. The blossom of the tree is called kahika. The pōhutukawa has been introduced to other countries with mild-to-warm climates, including south-eastern Australia, where it is naturalising on coastal cliffs near Sydney. In coastal California, it is a popular street and lawn tree, but has caused concern in San Francisco where its root systems are blamed for destroying sewer lines and sidewalks. In parts of South Africa, the pōhutukawa grows so well that it is regarded as an invasive species.  Pohuukawa are widespread in the Azores and in places in Galicia. The Spanish city of A Coruña has adopted the pōhutukawa as a floral emblem.</abstract>
    </species>
</species-list>
